<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="disclaimer">
        Please note that The Witcher Tabletop RPG\'s rules and mechanics differ from
        traditional Dungeons and Dragons. This application serves as a tool meant to be used
        alongside The Witcher Tabletop RPG Core Rulebook and follows the rules and mechanics set
        by it. Use of The Witcher Tabletop RPG Core Rulebook
        is strongly recommended as this application does not contain all of the
        information necessary to learn how to play. This is an unofficial application and is not
        approved/endorsed by CD PROJEKT RED or R. Talsorian Games. This application is not a
        licensed product. I do not claim ownership of any information, icons, or images used throughout
        the app. Copyrights and/or trademarks of any information, icons, and/or images used belong
        to their respective owners.
    </string>

    <string name="about">
        Thank you for downloading The Witcher TRPG Companion App. This application is a passion/learning
        project and it is meant to speed up character creation and role-playing while playing
        The Witcher Tabletop RPG. Since I am the sole contributor to the application,
        some key features have not been implemented to reduce complexity and development time. Some of which
        include crafting, armor/weapon enhancements, and mutations. I have implemented alternatives such as
        custom items, equipment notes, and stat/skill modifiers to have a similar functionality as said features.
        If you have any feedback or concerns regarding the application or it\'s content, please do not hesitate
        to leave a review and I will try to respond to it as soon as possible.
    </string>

    <string name="characterInformation_info">
        This is the character information section. Here you will be able to access common stats such
        as your current health, stamina, and crowns. You can also add a character image, access information regarding your
        profession, edit character personal information, and add background events. To navigate through the
        rest of the application, tap the navigation drawer icon at the top left of the screen.
    </string>

    <string name="characterSkills_info">
        This is the character skills section. Skills
        can have between 0 and 10 points in them
        and can never go higher than 10 points.
        Bonuses like racial modifiers can raise a
        skill above 10. When first making your
        character, your skills cap at 6. To increase a skill point,
        the current level of that skill will be subtracted from your improvement
        point total. To edit a skill\'s modifier, click and hold on the skill until
        the modifier indicator appears next to the skill level. Keep in mind that modifiers
        do not reduce your improvement points total and are usually obtained from racial perks, items,
        equipment, injuries, or consumables.
    </string>

    <string name="characterStats_info">
        This is the statistics section. The Statistic
        Cap is 10, however, Mutations and Racial
        traits can raise Statistics above
        this cap. The numbers displayed include your raw stat
        value plus any modifiers. To edit a stat\'s modifier, click and hold a stat until
        the modifier is shown. Keep in mind that modifiers
        do not reduce your improvement points total and are usually obtained from racial perks, items,
        equipment, injuries, or consumables.
    </string>

    <string-array name="races_array">
        <item>Human</item>
        <item>Dwarf</item>
        <item>Elf</item>
        <item>Witcher</item>
        <item>Halfling</item>
        <item>Gnome</item>
        <item>Vran</item>
        <item>Werebbub</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gender_array">
        <item>Male</item>
        <item>Female</item>
        <item>Non-Binary</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="prof_array">
        <item>Bard</item>
        <item>Criminal</item>
        <item>Craftsman</item>
        <item>Doctor</item>
        <item>Mage</item>
        <item>Man At Arms</item>
        <item>Priest</item>
        <item>Witcher</item>
        <item>Merchant</item>
        <item>Noble</item>
        <item>Peasant</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="standings_array">
        <item>Equal</item>
        <item>Tolerated</item>
        <item>Feared</item>
        <item>Hated</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>