<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="hexes_list_data">

        <item>The Hex of Shadows:4:The Hex of Shadows creates whispers in the
            shadows, and silhouettes around corners. The subject
            must make random Awareness checks with an
            unspecified DC, always almost catching a glimpse
            of something or someone. The awareness checks are
            never a real threat, just visions.
            :Low:The subject must bring a bowl
            of clear water, a branch from a white myrtle bush, and
            a bottle of ink to a clearing under a crescent moon.
            When the moon is at its highest the subject must pour
            the ink into the water, dip the branch in the mixture,
            and shake droplets in a circle around themselves while
            holding their breath.</item>

        <item>The Eternal Itch:4:The Eternal Itch causes inflamed,
            itchy pustules to grow on the subjects genitals. The itch does
            no damage but is a constant annoyance, causing a -1
            to all tasks. As well as this -1 the target takes a -5 to
            Seduction once in the bedroom.
            :Low:The subject must gather a unit
            of scleroderm, fool\'s parsely, and bryonia. The subject
            must light a campfire and bundle up the herbs. With
            everything prepared the subject must light the herbs
            and crumble the burning ashes onto the afflicted area
            while reciting a series of magic words.</item>

        <item>Curse of Temperance:4:The Curse of Temperance sours
            the subject\'s stomach to alcohol and exacerbates the
            effects of drunkenness. If the subject consumes anything
            that would cause them to become intoxicated, they
            immediately suffer the Intoxication and Nausea
            effects as their head spins and their stomach churns violently.
            :Low:The subject must gather 40 Crowns worth of alcohol
            and find a bucket. They must then fill the bucket with
            the alcohol and dunk their head. Their head must remain
            submerged until they suffer the Suffocation effect.
            Upon pulling their head from the bucket the hex will be broken.:toc</item>

        <item>The Odious Hex:4:The Odious Hex weaves around a subject
            and makes them repellent. While hexed, the subject always
            counts as one level lower on the Social Standing table
            unless they were already Hated. This affects people
            of the subject\'s own race.
            :Low:The subject must construct an effigy of
            themselves from a unit each of Han Fiber,
            Barley, and Fool\'s Parsley. They must then
            insult the effigy as if they were insulting
            themselves until they can no longer think of
            insults. Finally, the subject must burn the
            effigy to free themselves of the hex.:toc</item>

        <item>The Devil\'s Luck:8:The Devil’s Luck
            plagues the subject with bouts
            of bad fortune. In situations of high stress such as
            combat or when performing any task with a deadline
            or a DC higher than 15, the subject rolls a fumble on
            a natural 1 or 2.
            :Medium:The subject must hammer a
            silver nail into their door frame and hang 2 units of
            wolvesbane, tied with a lock of virgin’s hair, from it.
            Finally the subject must stand under the silver nail,
            set fire to the bundle of wolvesbane and virgin hair,
            and breath deeply.</item>

        <item>The Nightmare:8:The Nightmare forces the subject to relive the
            same horrifying nightmare. Every night the subject
            must make a Resist Coercion check at a DC equal to
            the Hex Weaving roll the caster made to hex them. If
            they succeed they manage to get a full, though restless,
            night’s sleep. If they fail, they barely sleep and do
            not recover STA or HP during the night. If they fail 3
            nights in a row they halve their Stamina and take a -2
            to all actions until they can get a full night’s rest.
            :Medium:The subject must gather 5 candles, 5 units
            of beast bones, and 1 unit of glowing ore.
            The night of the ceremony the subject must arrange
            the candles in a circle around them, linked by bones,
            and place the glowing ore under their head. If the
            subject is able to sleep through the night they will be
            freed of the hex.</item>

        <item>The Evil Eye:8:Casting The Evil Eye upon a subject
            weaves a web of misfortune around them which
            threatens their every move. Whenever the subject
            rolls a Fumble, they must roll twice and take
            the worse outcome. Additionally, the GM is
            encouraged to choose the subject whenever
            they would be randomly determining the target of a threat.
            :Medium:The subject must acquire a unit of coral from
            the Great Sea (50 Crowns) and fashion it into an
            amulet with a DC-14 Fine Arts check. The amulet
            must be worn during the entirety of a full moon
            and will shatter at the sunrise, freeing you of the Hex.:toc</item>

        <item>Unending Need:8:Unending Need causes the subject\'s
            body to be consumed by sloth and gluttony, requiring
            more sleep and food to function properly. The subject
            must get 10 hours of uninterrupted sleep each night
            or take the -3 penalty on rolls for Sleep-Deprivation.
            Additionally, the subject must eat 5 meals a day
            or halve their total STA for the next day.
            :Medium:The subject must fast for 3 full days and
            3 nights drinking only water and sleeping with sweets
            underneath their pillow. If the subject is able to
            perform this fast and not touch the sweets beneath
            their pillow the hex breaks on the morning of the fourth day.:toc</item>

        <item>The Pesta\'s Kiss:12:The Pesta’s Kiss breaks
            down the subject’s ability to fight illness and
            resist nausea. Anytime the subject comes in
            contact with a diseased person they have
            a 75% chance of catching the illness. Any time they
            smell something even slightly nauseating they must
            succeed at a DC of 16 Endurance check or be nauseated.
            :High:The subject must gather 3 units
            of river clay, 1 unit of coal, 3 units of resin, and 1 unit
            of infused dust. First the subject must craft a totem
            from the clay mixed with infused dust and coated
            in resin, with the coal forming its eyes. This takes a
            DC of 14 Fine Arts roll. Then the subject must repeat a
            series of magic words, infusing the totem with power.
            Immediately after, the totem must be smashed and
            the coal eyes must be powdered and consumed by the
            subject.</item>

        <item>The Hex of the Beast:12:The Hex of the Beast
            makes the target anathema to animals and beasts.
            Any time the target comes
            within 10m of an animal that animal will react poorly
            to the subject, giving them a -3 to Wilderness Survival
            for handling animals. Each time they come within
            10m of an animal there is a 50% chance the animal
            will attack.
            :High:The subject must gather a small
            live animal of some sort, 2 units of mistletoe, 1 unit
            of phosphorus, 2 units of crow’s eye, 3 units of mandrake
            root. Under a full moon the subject must cut
            the throat of the animal and consume its blood. Then
            the animal’s body must be wrapped in bundles of mistletoe,
            crow’s eye, and mandrake root and placed in
            an open fire. As the scales or fur of the animal start to
            burn away, the phosphorus must be thrown into the
            fire. When the fire has burned out the subject must
            remove the bones of the animal and wear them on their
            person for a full day.</item>

        <item>Bones of Glass:12:Bones of Glass magically hollows the
            bones of the subject, making them prone to splintering.
            When the subject would suffer the Cracked Ribs Critical
            Wound, they instead suffer the Broken Ribs Critical Wound.
            When they would suffer the Fractured Arm/Leg Critical
            Wounds they instead suffer the Compound Arm/Leg Fracture
            Critical Wounds. When they would suffer the Minor Head
            Wound Critical Wound, they instead suffer the Skull
            Fracture Critical Wound. Additionally, rolls made to
            stabilize or treat these critical wounds are
            made at a -3 penalty.
            :High:The subject must acquire a war horse, a troll liver,
            meat from a wolf, 3 units of balisse leaves, and a bottle
            of spirits. Upon gathering these things, the subject must
            bleed the war horse, collecting some of the blood in a pot
            and add the liver, meat, and leaves to form a foul stew
            which takes 3 hours to cook. The subject must then consume
            the entire pot of stew within 1 hour and follow it by
            chugging the bottle of spirits. When they finish the
            bottle, the hex will have been lifted.:toc</item>

        <item>Hex of Forgetfulness:12:The Hex of Forgetfulness submerges
            the subjects mind in a thick soup of magical obscurement
            making it difficult for them to retain knowledge and memories.
            The subject can no longer gain I.P. via being taught or study
            and practice, can no longer teach someone, and can no longer
            learn new magic. Additionally, once per day, the GM can call
            upon the subject to make a Resist Magic roll at a DC-20 or
            forget a fact, memory, recipe, spell, invocation, ritual,
            hex, or sign of the GM\'s choice until the Hex is removed.
            :High:The subject must shave their head of all hair and
            then prepare a paste of 2 units of essence of water
            and 2 units of river clay. The subject must then
            inscribe specific sigils on their scalp with the
            clay and hold a unit of optima matter under their
            tongue. They must wait silently for a full day and
            night for the clay to dry. When the clay is removed
            from the scalp and the optima matter is removed from
            their mouth, the optima matter will be ashen gray and
            the hex will have been removed, returning anything forgotten.
            The optima matter used is permanently grayed and acts as a
            Focus (2) that can only be used for Hexes, Goetia, and
            Necromancy.:toc</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>