<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="hexes_list_data">

        <item>The Hex of Shadows:4:The Hex of Shadows creates whispers in the
            shadows, and silhouettes around corners. The subject
            must make random Awareness checks with an
            unspecified DC, always almost catching a glimpse
            of something or someone. The awareness checks are
            never a real threat, just visions.
            :Low:The subject must bring a bowl
            of clear water, a branch from a white myrtle bush, and
            a bottle of ink to a clearing under a crescent moon.
            When the moon is at its highest the subject must pour
            the ink into the water, dip the branch in the mixture,
            and shake droplets in a circle around themselves while
            holding their breath.</item>

        <item>The Eternal Itch:4:The Eternal Itch causes inflamed,
            itchy pustules to grow on the subjects genitals. The itch does
            no damage but is a constant annoyance, causing a -1
            to all tasks. As well as this -1 the target takes a -5 to
            Seduction once in the bedroom.
            :Low:The subject must gather a unit
            of scleroderm, fool’s parsely, and bryonia. The subject
            must light a campfire and bundle up the herbs. With
            everything prepared the subject must light the herbs
            and crumble the burning ashes onto the afflicted area
            while reciting a series of magic words.</item>

        <item>The Devil\'s Luck:8:The Devil’s Luck
            plagues the subject with bouts
            of bad fortune. In situations of high stress such as
            combat or when performing any task with a deadline
            or a DC higher than 15, the subject rolls a fumble on
            a natural 1 or 2.
            :Medium:The subject must hammer a
            silver nail into their door frame and hang 2 units of
            wolvesbane, tied with a lock of virgin’s hair, from it.
            Finally the subject must stand under the silver nail,
            set fire to the bundle of wolvesbane and virgin hair,
            and breath deeply.</item>

        <item>The Nightmare:8:The Nightmare forces the subject to relive the
            same horrifying nightmare. Every night the subject
            must make a Resist Coercion check at a DC equal to
            the Hex Weaving roll the caster made to hex them. If
            they succeed they manage to get a full, though restless,
            night’s sleep. If they fail, they barely sleep and do
            not recover STA or HP during the night. If they fail 3
            nights in a row they halve their Stamina and take a -2
            to all actions until they can get a full night’s rest.
            :Medium:The subject must gather 5 candles, 5 units
            of beast bones, and 1 unit of glowing ore.
            The night of the ceremony the subject must arrange
            the candles in a circle around them, linked by bones,
            and place the glowing ore under their head. If the
            subject is able to sleep through the night they will be
            freed of the hex.</item>

        <item>The Pesta\'s Kiss:12:The Pesta’s Kiss breaks
            down the subject’s ability to fight illness and
            resist nausea. Anytime the subject comes in
            contact with a diseased person they have
            a 75% chance of catching the illness. Any time they
            smell something even slightly nauseating they must
            succeed at a DC of 16 Endurance check or be nauseated.
            :High:The subject must gather 3 units
            of river clay, 1 unit of coal, 3 units of resin, and 1 unit
            of infused dust. First the subject must craft a totem
            from the clay mixed with infused dust and coated
            in resin, with the coal forming its eyes. This takes a
            DC of 14 Fine Arts roll. Then the subject must repeat a
            series of magic words, infusing the totem with power.
            Immediately after, the totem must be smashed and
            the coal eyes must be powdered and consumed by the
            subject.</item>

        <item>The Hex of the Beast:12:The Hex of the Beast
            makes the target anathema to animals and beasts.
            Any time the target comes
            within 10m of an animal that animal will react poorly
            to the subject, giving them a -3 to Wilderness Survival
            for handling animals. Each time they come within
            10m of an animal there is a 50% chance the animal
            will attack.
            :High:The subject must gather a small
            live animal of some sort, 2 units of mistletoe, 1 unit
            of phosphorus, 2 units of crow’s eye, 3 units of mandrake
            root. Under a full moon the subject must cut
            the throat of the animal and consume its blood. Then
            the animal’s body must be wrapped in bundles of mistletoe,
            crow’s eye, and mandrake root and placed in
            an open fire. As the scales or fur of the animal start to
            burn away, the phosphorus must be thrown into the
            fire. When the fire has burned out the subject must
            remove the bones of the animal and wear them on their
            person for a full day.</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>