<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="novice_druidInvo_list_data">

        <item>Boiling Blood:3:Boiling Blood causes an
            animal or non-sentient monster
            within range to become enraged
            at a target. The creature will try to
            attack the chosen target until the
            duration ends.
            :8m:1d10 Rounds:Creature\'s WILLx3</item>

        <item>Cursed Illness:Variable:Cursed Illness causes one
            target to fall ill. The illness manifests differently based on how
            many Stamina points are spent.
            2 points causes the target to double over coughing and staggers
            them. 4 points causes the target
            to become violently ill, stunning
            them. 6 points causes the target to
            become ill with a ravaging disease
            which is treated as a poison. The
            invocation ends when the target
            makes an Endurance roll at a DC
            equal to the casting roll.
            :8m:Endurance Roll Ends:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Friend to Wild Kind:1:Friend to Wild Kind grants
            the caster a +3 to Wilderness Survival
            for handling animals. Alternately it can calm one animal if
            the Spell Casting roll exceeds the animal’s WILLx3.
            :Self or 5m:1d6 Hours:Creature\'s WILLx3</item>

        <item>Herbalism:2:Herbalism allows you to create an elixir
            using ancient druidic practices instead of traditional
            alchemy. As long as all the ingredients for the elixir
            are plants, you can roll a Spell Casting check instead
            of an Alchemy check when creating the Elixir or in the
            Recovery step.
            :2m:Immediate:None:toc</item>

        <item>Nature\'s Gift:Variable:Nature\'s Gift grows a small
            cluster of edible plants in soil of
            any kind. These plants are enough
            to sustain a number of people
            equal to the number of STA points
            spent for 1 day.
            :2m:Immediate:None</item>

        <item>Nature\'s Sight:2:Nature’s Sight allows you
            to see creatures that are not natural
            to this realm. This allows you
            to see monsters within 50m, even
            through obstacles. Monsters seen
            in this view appears as glowing
            versions of themselves.
            :Self:Active (1 STA):None</item>

        <item>Sigil of Bounty:1:Widely used by druids who advise
            rural communities, Sigil of Bounty imbues an
            aspect of nature with vigor to cause one of three
            effects. If cast on spoiled food or drink, this invocation
            causes them to become fresh and delicious again.
            If cast on a forageable plant, the plant will produce
            twice the units of forageable material. Finally, if cast
            on soil, any plant grown in the soil will grow to twice
            its typical size in half the time.
            :2m:1 Year:None:toc</item>

        <item>Sigil of the Hidden:2:Drawing the Sigil of the
            Hidden covers a 3m area in
            branches, foliage, and other natural
            elements to provide complete
            visual cover. This grants you a +5
            to Stealth, but immobilizes those
            inside and must be cast again to
            uncover yourself. You can cut
            away the brush by doing 10 points
            of damage to it.
            :Self:Until Dispelled:None</item>

        <item>Voice of the Counselor:3:Voice of the Counselor
            allows you to imbue your words with inspiration.
            For the duration of this invocation, you can either
            make your voice boom loud enough to be heard from
            far away or whisper in the ear of one person within
            range. Additionally, you gain a +4 to Leadership checks.
            :10m:10 Minutes:None:toc</item>

        <item>Web of Roots:2:Web of Roots allows you to take control
            of the roots of a nearby tree to grapple a target. Upon
            casting this invocation on a tree, you can use its roots
            to grapple, trip, or disarm a target within 10m of the
            tree who fails a Defense check against your Spell Casting
            check. Each round that you maintain this invocation you
            can either maintain your grapple or attempt one of the
            other options on a target within 10m of the tree. A grappled
            target can escape by succeeding a Dodge/Escape check against
            a new Spell Casting check or by dealing 15 points of damage to the roots.
            :10m:Active (1 STA):None:toc</item>

        <item>Word of Summoning:Variable:Speaking the Word of Summoning
            calls out to a nearby wild animal which arrives within
            1d6 rounds. When the animal arrives, it is friendly to you
            and will help you as long as you don\'t betray or abuse it.
            If you spend 2 STA casting Word of Summoning you can summon
            a small animal (Bird, Serpent, Cat, etc.). If you spend 5
            STA you can summon a medium animal (Wolves, Panthers, Boars, etc.).
            If you spend 10 STA you can summon a large animal
            (Bear, Ox, Horse, etc.). Word of Summoning can only be cast
            once in an area per day. When this invocation ends, the
            animal becomes neutral to you.
            :N/A:10 Minutes:None:toc</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="journeyman_druidInvo_list_data">

        <item>Bigelow\'s Befoulment:Variable:Bigelow\'s
            Befoulment taints all food or drink you desire
            within a 2m cubed area with harmful bacteria. If
            you spend 5 STA casting this invocation, anyone
            who consumes the affected food or drink suffers
            the Disease condition within the next hour. While
            affected by the Disease condition, a target takes
            a -2 to all actions, lowers their maximum STA by one
            quarter, and must make DC-14 Endurance checks at the
            discretion of the Game Master or suffer the Nausea condition. The
            Disease condition can only be removed by having a
            Doctor roll a DC-15 Healing Hands check on the
            affected character and then that character
            getting a full night\'s rest. If you spend 10
            STA casting this invocation, the affected targets
            also suffer the Poison condition.
            :4m:Permanent:None:toc</item>

        <item>Blessing of Healing:5:Blessing of Healing
            jumpstarts a target\'s healing, allowing
            them to heal at 3 points per round.
            This blessing can be used multiple
            times to heal a critical wound.
            :2m:Active (3 STA):None</item>

        <item>Blood of the Mountain:6:Calling upon the wellspring
            of power deep within the earth, Blood of the Mountain
            empowers a target with tremendous strength.
            The target\'s melee attacks cannot be parried and deal
            double ablation damage to weapons, shields, and armor.
            Additionally, the target is immune to any effect that
            would knock them off their feet.
            :6m:10 Minutes:None:toc</item>

        <item>Primal Reservoir:6:Primal Reservoir allows
            you to tap into the primal power
            of a target and awaken it. It grants
            them a +2 to Melee Damage, but a
            -2 to INT for the duration of the
            spell.
            :5m:2d6 Rounds:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Sigil of the Hunt:5:Drawing the Sigil of the Hunt
            on a target allows you to change how animals and monsters
            perceive them. Upon casting this Invocation, you can mark
            up to 6 targets as either "safe" or "prey". A target marked
            "safe" does not disturb animals and any beast they encounter
            is initially friendly; and any monster they encounter
            will initially be neutral. A target marked "prey" is perceived
            as prey by all predatory animals or monsters. These creatures
            will attack the target on sight. Both "Prey" and "Safe"
            marks appear almost identical but with a DC-16 Education
            check, you can tell the difference.
            :2m:1 Day:Resist Magic:toc</item>

        <item>Threads of Life:4:Threads of Life allows you
            to see the life energy binding every
            target within the radius of the
            spell, which tells you their current Health Points and any critical
            wounds they have suffered.
            :10m:Active (2 STA):None</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="master_druidInvo_data">

        <item>Druidic Totem:14:Druidic Totem allows you to sacrifice
            your staff of oak and mistletoe to create a magical totem
            which connects you to the natural world. After casting this
            Invocation, you must sacrifice the focus created by the Rite
            of Oak and Mistletoe by planting it in the ground. The staff
            grows into a 2m tall totem with 20 Hit Points, reminiscent of
            the local flora. While within 1-Mile of this totem, you are
            always counted as having a focus with a value of 4, all animals
            are considered friendly to you and your allies, and you gain
            an additional benefit based on the location where you placed
            the totem. You can only have one totem active at a time and
            creating a new totem transforms the old totem into a non-magical
            plant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Fields- You have a Speed Statistic of 12. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Mountains- You have Resistance to Bludgeoning,
            Slashing and Piercing damage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Underground- You have Superior Night Vision and
            gain a +4 to Stealth checks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Forest- If you consume fruit grown within the area of your totem,
            you gain a Regeneration value of 3 for 1 Hour.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Swamp- You are immune to the Poison and Disease conditions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Shore- You can breath underwater and have no penalties
            for fighting or maneuvering in water.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Desert- You are immune to the Extreme Heat condition
            and you can always find a source of water. Once per day,
            when you consume water collected within the area of
            your totem, you regain all lost STA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Tundra- You are immune to the Snow and Ice conditions,
            you cannot be lit on fire or frozen, and you
            gain resistance to fire and ice damage.

            :2m:Immediate:None:toc</item>

        <item>Shape Nature:12:Shape Nature allows you to create a golem
            from a small nearby tree. The golem serves you for
            the duration of the spell and will turn back into a
            tree when the duration ends. If killed, the golem only
            yields 2d10 units of timber. In all other ways, the tree
            acts as a normal golem.
            :10m:1d10 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Song of the Sky:10:The Song of the Sky changes the weather in the
            area directly around you. You can change the weather
            to clear sky (no modifiers), cloudy (little sunlight),
            rainstorm (puts out fires), wind storm (-2 to DEX for
            ranged attacks), or lightning storm (35% chance of
            being struck by lightning, equivalent to the Lightning
            Storm spell).
            :50m:Active (5 STA):None</item>

        <item>Wrath of Nature:14:Wrath of Nature allows you to summon the
            tremendous power of the natural world to wreak
            havoc on your enemies. Depending on the terrain,
            Wrath of Nature creates a different effect centered on you with a 60m radius.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Fields- Every turn you can spend a full round action to either touch down
            a rope tornado within 10m of you or direct a single rope tornado within
            the area of the storm. A rope tornado covers a 4m cubed area and when
            directed by you can move 10m per turn. If it runs over or into targets
            those targets must make Athletics checks against your Spell Casting check.
            If they fail, they take 4d6 damage to the torso and are knocked back 10m
            in a direction decided by the GM.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Mountains- Every turn you can spend a full round action to summon
            down a bolt of lightning which strikes a target. The target must
            make a Dodge/Escape or Athletics check against your Spell Casting
            check or take 6d6 damage to the torso and have a 50% chance of being
            lit on fire.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Underground- Every turn you can spend a full round action
            to summon a stalagmite or stalactite to violently erupt from the stone
            and stab a single target. The target of this attack must make a Dodge/Escape,
            Athletics, or Block check against your Spell Casting check or take 5d6 damage.
            Each summoned stalagmite or stalactite remains until destroyed and counts as
            a 2m cubed piece of cover with 20 SP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Forest- Every turn you can spend a full round action to either summon
            up a tangle of roots from the ground to take one of the following
            actions or give a single command to each existing tangle of roots
            you have summoned. These roots are immobile but have the Long Reach
            Effect and can be used to Grapple, Trip, Disarm, Choke, or Pin a
            target. They have a Brawling base of 16 unless your Spell Casting
            base would be higher.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Swamp- Every turn you can spend a full round action to summon a 6m radius
            area of swamp gas that erupts from the ground. Anyone caught in the gas
            must make an Endurance check against your Spell Casting check or suffer
            from the Disease condition. This gas remains until the invocation ends.
            Additionally, if an exposed flame is present in the area of this gas, it
            explodes, causing every creature in the gas to take 5d6 damage to the torso
            and have a 75% chance of catching on fire.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Shore- Every turn you can spend a full round action to summon a
            powerful waterspout out of the nearby body of water to knock down
            targets with pressurized water. Two jets of water emit from the spout
            towards one or two targets within 20m. These target\'s must make
            Dodge/Escape or Athletics checks against your Spell Casting check
            or take 3d6 damage and be knocked back 6m.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Desert- Every turn you can spend a full round action to kick up
            a gust of burning sand in a 6m radius area. Any creatures within
            this area must make a Dodge/Escape or Athletics check versus your
            Spell Casting check or be blinded for 5 rounds and be lit on fire.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

            Tundra- Every turn you can spend a full round action to summon up
            a whirl of snow and water magic around a single target to encase
            them in ice. The target must make a Dodge/Escape, Athletics, or
            Resist Magic check versus your Spell Casting check or be encased
            in solid ice. This ice immobilizes the target and keeps them from
            taking actions. To break out of this ice, the target must make a
            DC-16 Physique check. Alternatively, if someone deals 10 points of
            damage to the ice or 5 points of fire damage to the ice, it allows
            the person to break free. Any damage beyond the 10 points (or 5 points)
            required to break the ice is dealt to the target\'s torso.

            :60m:Active (6 STA):Variable:toc</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hierophant_flaminika_priestInvo_list_data">

        <item>Shade of Bleobheris (Bleobheris):16:Shade of Bleobheris calls
            upon the great oak to calm the hearts of man and beast.
            Upon casting this invocation, all animals become docile
            and all affected combatants are removed from initiative and
            cannot take hostile actions for 1 day. Additionally, the
            essence of Bleobheris temporarily suppresses the prejudices
            of all affected creatures, negating any penalties from Social
            Standing or monstrous heritage. On each of its turns, a target
            affected by this invocation can use its action to attempt a
            Resist Magic check against a new Spell Casting check to end
            this effect. If the target is attacked this spell no longer
            affects them.
            :50m Radius:1 Day:Resist Magic:toc</item>

        <item>Winds of the Taiga (Gwyn Carn):16:Winds of the Taiga summons
            the winter winds of the Far North to create a blizzard that
            shelters you and your allies. The area of the invocation
            is immersed in a blizzard that blinds anyone in it and
            creates Snow and Ice conditions. Any number of people
            you choose are not blinded by the blizzard, are immune
            to the Snow and Ice conditions, and their attacks
            have an additional 50% chance of freezing.
            :1 Mile Radius:1 Hour:None:toc</item>

        <item>Sanctuary of the Black Grove (Caed Myrkvid):16:Sanctuary
            of the Black Grove allows you to attune yourself and as
            many allies as you wish to the trees within a 1 Mile radius.
            While this invocation is active, you can touch a tree and
            look simultaneously through all the trees within 1 mile
            of you. You are able to parse this information and focus
            on specific views if you want. Additionally, you and any
            allies you designate can pass through any tree within this
            area and come out of any another tree within the area.
            Your allies cannot see through the trees but are able
            to designate where they want to go.
            :1 Mile Radius:1 Hour:Dodge:toc</item>

        <item>Well of Knowledge (Gedyneith):16:Well of Knowledge causes
            a tree you touch to grow an integrated basin of fluorescing
            water blessed by nature. The next 20 people to drink from
            this basin are affected immediately. For one day after consuming
            the water of the basin, a creature gains a +4 to Initiative
            and Awareness, becomes immune to the Stagger, Stun, and Hallucination
            conditions, and can see through any illusions. If the creature
            had a Vigor Threshold of one or more before consuming the
            water, they raise their Vigor Threshold by 4 but suffer a -4
            to Resist Magic. After the invocation ends, the tree shifts
            back to normal leaving only an etched sigil unique to the
            druid. A creature cannot benefit from this invocation more
            than once a week.
            :2m:1 Day:None:toc</item>


    </string-array>

    <string-array name="novice_priestInvo_list_data">

        <item>Blessed Weapon:2:Blessed Weapon creates a glowing
            rune on a melee weapon you touch which magically
            lightens and balances the weapon. For the duration
            of the invocation, the weapon has the Balanced Effect.
            :2m:30 Minutes:None:toc</item>

        <item>Blessing of Fortune:1:The Blessing of Fortune
            gives the target LUCK points equal
            to half the value you rolled over
            DC of 12 (max 5).
            :10m:Until Expired:None</item>

        <item>Blessing of Love:2:The Blessing of Love gives
            the caster a +3 to Charisma and
            Seduction for the duration of the
            invocation.
            :5m:1d10 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Divine Inspiration:2:Common among inquisitors
            and artists alike, Divine Inspiration allows
            you to bless a target with insight. Upon casting
            this invocation, you grant a +2 bonus to a single
            skill. The target of this invocation must have at
            least a Skill value of 1 in the skill affected
            before the invocation is cast. A character can
            only benefit from this invocation once per day.
            :8m:10 Minutes:None:toc</item>

        <item>Duplicitous Darkness:2:Duplicitous Darkness
            shrouds your target\'s mind in a veil of false thoughts.
            Your target gains a +2 to Deceit checks, cannot be
            forced to tell the truth by magic, and cannot be mentally
            spied on with Telepathy. Anyone attempting to probe the
            target with magic is unaware that this invocation has
            been cast unless they make a DC-20 Awareness check.
            :2m:1 Hour:None:toc</item>

        <item>Light of Penance:3:Developed by the beloved Incandescent
            Anika var Myricks in the heart of Nilfgaard, Light
            of Penance summons the power of your deity to punish
            a target, draining them of their will to resist.
            Upon casting this invocation, the target lowers
            their current STA by 2d6. If the target has a Vigor
            Threshold of 1 or higher, they lower their current
            STA by an additional 2d6 as well.
            :6m:Immediate:Resist Magic:toc</item>

        <item>Holy Light:1:Holy Light lights up an area
            as though the caster was carrying
            a torch. The light gives off no heat
            and cannot be used to ignite other
            objects like a torch can.
            :Self:3d10 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Presence of the Divine:3:Presence of the Divine
            allows you to summon the aspect of your deity to
            make your bearing more imposing. Upon casting this
            invocation, you can make your voice boom loud enough
            to be heard from far away and you gain a +4 to
            Intimidation checks. Alternatively, this invocation
            can be cast on up to 6 targets to make them immune to fear effects.
            :10m:10 Minutes:None:toc</item>

        <item>Vaults of Knowledge:3:Vaults of Knowledge
            allows you to reach back into your
            mind and access any knowledge or
            memory that you’ve ever known as
            if you were just experiencing it.
            :Self:Immediate:None</item>

        <item>Waters of Clearance:1:Waters of Clearance sobers
            the target immediately. This incantation counteracts alcohol and
            alchemical solutions that cause intoxication.
            :5m:Immediate:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Web of Lies:3:Web of Lies allows you to
            scramble the information in a target’s head, making them question
            every piece of information and
            memory. This stuns the target.
            Once per round, on their turn, the
            target can roll 1d10. If they roll under their INT the effect ends.
            :8m:INT roll ends:Resist Magic</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="journeyman_priestInvo_list_data">

        <item>Blessing of Abundance:6:Blessing of Abundance
            imbues you with divine providence, making you more
            likely to benefit from found goods. The first time
            you or your GM rolls to determine how much loot you
            gain, the roll is made twice and the higher value
            is taken. This applies to an entire loot source,
            meaning that if you loot a dead monster, you would
            roll each loot item twice and take the higher value.
            :Self:1 Day:None:toc</item>

        <item>Brand of Withering:6:Favored by death cultists of
            all creeds, Brand of Withering marks a target
            with a symbol of creeping decay that arrests their
            ability to heal. Upon casting this invocation, a
            target who failed to defend can no longer benefit from any
            effect that would allow them to recover Hit Points,
            including natural healing.
            :8m:1 Week:Resist Magic:toc</item>

        <item>Cleansing Fire:6:Cleansing Fire ignites one
            target, doing 3d6 damage and setting them on fire.
            :10m:Until Put Out:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Holy Fortification:5:Holy Fortification bolsters
            a target’s willpower and allows the
            target to make a new check against
            the effects of any spell that is currently affecting them.
            :10m:Immediate:None</item>

        <item>Light of Truth:4:The Light of Truth allows
            you to create a bright white light
            that forces one target to speak
            truthfully. Every round the target
            must make another check. If they
            fail, they must answer any question truthfully.
            :5m:Active (2 STA):Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Seek the Seekers:6:Seek the Seekers creates a
            magical ward around you that warns you of divination
            such as Hydromancy, or Pyromancy. If you or anyone
            within 10m of you is the target of divination. you
            are alerted as soon as it is cast and are shown
            the face of the diviner. Anyone who tries to spy
            on you with divination must make a DC-20 Education
            or Magic Training check to realize they have been
            caught. However, if they succeed this check, you
            are made aware that they know you caught them.
            :Self:1 Day:None:toc</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="master_priestInvo_list_data">

        <item>Divine Portal:12:Divine Portal creates a standing portal for a
            brief instant. The portal lasts for just one round and
            allows you to transport yourself or others anywhere
            you can recall. This portal otherwise functions like the
            mage spell, Standing Portal.
            :N/A:1 Round:None</item>

        <item>Divine Wisdom:10:Divine Wisdom searches
            with a powerful augury for the answer to a question.
            This answer cannot predict the future.
            The GM sets your DC based on the secrecy of the information.
            :50m:Active (5 STA):None</item>

        <item>Quill of the Divine:Variable:Quill of the Divine allows
            you to reach into a target\'s mind and alter their memories.
            By spending 14 STA you can lock away the memories of a
            target who fails to defend against this invocation giving
            them severe retrograde amnesia. By spending 16 STA you can
            implant memories of your own creation into a target who
            fails to defend. Unless the target has had their memories
            locked away with this spell, they gain a +5 to resist
            the implantation of these new memories.
            :2m:Permanent:Resist Magic:toc</item>

        <item>Sagitta Aurea:14:Sagitta Aurea summons the divine
            power of your deity to form a spear of golden light.
            Upon casting this invocation, a target must make a Defense
            check against your Spell Casting check. If they fail,
            the target takes 7d6 damage. Sagitta Aurea can travel in
            a straight line through targets with each target making
            a Defense check. If a target is possessed by a demon,
            the demon takes the damage as well and is forced out of
            their body. Additionally, any demon damaged by this
            invocation cannot use any of its abilities for the next round.
            :20m:Immediate:Dodge:toc</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="archPriestInvo_list_data">

        <item>Blessed Herd (Epona):16:With power granted to you by Epona,
            you summon up to 10 wild horses and empower them with magic.
            These horses appear within the next hour. A horse empowered
            by this invocation can either be empowered with swiftness
            or strength. If enchanted with swiftness, the horse summoned
            is a Horse with a Speed Statistic of 24 and an Athletics
            Skill Base of 20. If enchanted with strength, the horse
            summoned is a Warhorse with a Control modifier of +2 and a natural
            armor value of 20 which can\'t be layered with barding. While
            riding these mounts, creatures you choose get a +5 to their
            riding checks. You can only have up to ten horses summoned
            with this invocation at a time.
            :N/A:1 Week:None:toc</item>

        <item>Blessing of Death:16:Summoning the power of the Lion-Headed
            Spider, you cut the ties of life holding a target to this
            world. The target must roll Resist Magic or be thrust
            into Death state as if by taking normal damage. However
            if they are treated with a successful First Aid or
            Healing Hands roll at a DC of 16, they immediately
            recover their previous number of Health Points.
            :10m:Immediate:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Blood of the Berserker (Svalblod):16:Channeling the power of
            Svalblod, you transform your body into a towering great bear.
            While in this form, any items on your person meld into your form
            and you gain access to all the abilities of the Great Bear
            but loose access to your Profession abilities and magic.
            Your Statistic and Skill values change to those a great
            bear with the exception of any values that would be higher
            than those of a Great Bear. When you end the effects of this
            invocation, any damage or Critical wound you took as a Great
            Bear are transferred to your natural body. However, if the
            damage sustained as a Great Bear would be enough to kill you
            normally you are instead reduced to 1 Hit Point. Similarly,
            when you cast this invocation, any damage or critical wounds
            you already had are applied to your Great Bear form.
            :Self:1 Day:None:toc</item>

        <item>Champion of The River (Veyopatis):16:With the power of Veyopatis
            you anoint with river water a target as your champion and suffuse
            them with magical strength. As long as this invocation is active,
            your champion has Resistance to all damage sources and gains a +5 to all rolls.
            :10m:Active (5 STA):None:toc</item>

        <item>Eternal Judgement:16:Using the power granted to you by the Eternal
            Fire, you cause a target to burst into a bright white
            fire, tinged with red. The fire does double the normal
            fire damage and cannot be extinguished except
            by magic, or by completely submerging underwater
            for 3 rounds. Anything that touches this magical fire
            ignites with normal fire and can be put out in one full round.
            :10m:Until Put Out:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Feast of Plenty (Dana Meadbh):16:Calling upon the power
            of the Lady of the Valley, you bless a feast gathered entirely
            from the local area and large enough to feed at least 20.
            Upon eating from this feast, a creature gains 6d6 Hit Points,
            immediately treats all critical wounds; and removes the
            Poison and Disease conditions. This invocation can affect
            as many people as the feast can feed.
            :2m:Immediate:None:toc</item>

        <item>Freya\' Bravery:16:Calling upon the power of the goddess Freya,
            you summon her spirit into your body, creating a
            glow around yourself which emanates 20m in all directions. Every
            person within that area is emboldened
            by Modron Freya\'s love and guidance. They become
            immune to fear and gain 25 Health Points for the duration of
            the spell. If they leave the area of the invocation, its effects
            last for 1d6 rounds. These rounds renew if the person
            re-enters the area of the invocation
            and leaves again. This invocation affects those who
            don\'t believe in Freya, but the power can be withheld
            from anyone the caster chooses.
            :20m Radius:20 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Healing Rest:16:With the power granted to you by Melitele, the
            mother goddess, you can place a number of people
            equal to the value of your Spell Casting skill into a
            deep coma in which their bodies heal themselves.
            They cannot act for the entirety of the rest and are
            unaware of their surroundings even if touched, moved,
            or attacked. At the end of the rest, targets revive at full
            health. If they had any critical wounds that had been
            treated, these wounds have been healed. This does not
            remove permanent penalties from Deadly Critical
            Wounds.
            :5m:1 Day:None</item>

        <item>Luck of the Father:16:With power granted to you by Kreve, the
            All-Father, you gather divine providence to you. For
            the duration of the spell you can spend a number of
            LUCK points equal to your Spell Casting skill value
            times 3. You can augment any rolls you make, but can
            also impose penalties or grant bonuses to the roll of
            anyone within 10m.
            :Self/10m:1 Hour:None</item>

        <item>Miracle of Lebioda (Lebioda):16:Calling upon the power of
            the Prophet Lebioda you command the body of a target to heal
            itself. Immediately upon casting this invocation, a living
            target entirely heals one critical wound or removes the
            lingering penalty from a past critical wound. The wound is
            treated as though it had never been inflicted even if this
            means regrowing limbs, eyes, etc.
            :2m:Immediate:None:toc</item>

        <item>Omens of the Future (Nehaleni):16:You allow Nehaleni
            to fill your mind with thousands of glimpses of possible
            futures which you cannot immediately decipher. Roll 1d10
            until you get 3 outcomes that are not 1 or 10 and record
            these numbers. For the duration of this invocation, if a
            target within 20m of you rolls one of these values on
            1d10 you are immediately able to recognize this outcome,
            allowing you to, without taking an action, intervene in
            some minor way and force that target to instead roll a fumble.
            :Self:1 Day:None:toc</item>

        <item>Retribution of the Raven (Morrigan):16:With power granted
            to you by Morrigan, the Lady of Ravens, you block the connection
            to the elemental planes, nullifying magic. Within the area
            of this invocation, all magical effects, such as runes, glyphs,
            focuses, curses, trophies, relics, magical items, etc. are rendered
            inert. As long as this invocation is active, only those you
            choose or those who successfully defended against this invocation
            can cast magic of any form. This invocation cannot be dispelled.
            :20m:Active (5 STA):Resist Magic:toc</item>

        <item>Silverlight (Lilvani):16:Summoning the power of the Moon Goddess
            Lilvani you anoint up to 5 people with the a blessing of moonlight
            which shelters them in their darkest hour. For the duration of this
            invocation, affected characters take no penalties from being within
            their Wound Threshold or in Death State and the first time they
            would be reduced to below 1 Hit Point they are instead reduced
            to 1 Hit Point.
            :2m:Until next sunrise:None:toc</item>

        <item>White Flame:16: Summoning the power of the Great Sun, you
            create a bright aura of White Fire which lights the surrounding
            area to the level of bright light. This aura of
            fire doesn\'t burn anyone who touches it but does thaw
            anyone in the spell’s area, and dispels water-based
            spells in the area. Water-based spells can only be cast
            in the area of the spell if the caster’s Spell Casting
            check beats that of the Priest of the Great Sun. On top
            of this, any monster in the area that is vulnerable to
            sunlight takes double the normal penalties.
            :10m Radius:1 Hour:Resist Magic</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>