<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="novice_druidInvo_list_data">

        <item>Boiling Blood:3:Boiling Blood causes an
            animal or non-sentient monster
            within range to become enraged
            at a target. The creature will try to
            attack the chosen target until the
            duration ends.
            :8m:1d10 Rounds:Creature\'s WILLx3</item>

        <item>Cursed Illness:Variable:Cursed Illness causes one
            target to fall ill. The illness manifests differently based on how
            many Stamina points are spent.
            2 points causes the target to double over coughing and staggers
            them. 4 points causes the target
            to become violently ill, stunning
            them. 6 points causes the target to
            become ill with a ravaging disease
            which is treated as a poison. The
            invocation ends when the target
            makes an Endurance roll at a DC
            equal to the casting roll.
            :8m:Endurance Roll Ends:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Friend to Wild Kind:1:Friend to Wild Kind grants
            the caster a +3 to Wilderness Survival
            for handling animals. Alternately it can calm one animal if
            the Spell Casting roll exceeds the animal’s WILLx3.
            :Self or 5m:1d6 Hours:Creature\'s WILLx3</item>

        <item>Nature\'s Gift:Variable:Nature\'s Gift grows a small
            cluster of edible plants in soil of
            any kind. These plants are enough
            to sustain a number of people
            equal to the number of STA points
            spent for 1 day.
            :2m:Immediate:None</item>

        <item>Nature\'s Sight:2:Nature’s Sight allows you
            to see creatures that are not natural
            to this realm. This allows you
            to see monsters within 50m, even
            through obstacles. Monsters seen
            in this view appears as glowing
            versions of themselves.
            :Self:Active (1 STA):None</item>

        <item>Sigil of the Hidden:2:Drawing the Sigil of the
            Hidden covers a 3m area in
            branches, foliage, and other natural
            elements to provide complete
            visual cover. This grants you a +5
            to Stealth, but immobilizes those
            inside and must be cast again to
            uncover yourself. You can cut
            away the brush by doing 10 points
            of damage to it.
            :Self:Until Dispelled:None</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="journeyman_druidInvo_list_data">

        <item>Blessing of Healing:5:Blessing of Healing
            jumpstarts a target\'s healing, allowing
            them to heal at 3 points per round.
            This blessing can be used multiple
            times to heal a critical wound.
            :2m:Active (3 STA):None</item>

        <item>Primal Reservoir:6:Primal Reservoir allows
            you to tap into the primal power
            of a target and awaken it. It grants
            them a +2 to Melee Damage, but a
            -2 to INT for the duration of the
            spell.
            :5m:2d6 Rounds:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Threads of Life:4:Threads of Life allows you
            to see the life energy binding every
            target within the radius of the
            spell, which tells you their current Health Points and any critical
            wounds they have suffered.
            :10m:Active (2 STA):None</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="master_druidInvo_data">

        <item>Shape Nature:12:Shape Nature allows you to create a golem
            from a small nearby tree. The golem serves you for
            the duration of the spell and will turn back into a
            tree when the duration ends. If killed, the golem only
            yields 2d10 units of timber. In all other ways, the tree
            acts as a normal golem.
            :10m:1d10 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Song of the Sky:10:The Song of the Sky changes the weather in the
            area directly around you. You can change the weather
            to clear sky (no modifiers), cloudy (little sunlight),
            rainstorm (puts out fires), wind storm (-2 to DEX for
            ranged attacks), or lightning storm (35% chance of
            being struck by lightning, equivalent to the Lightning
            Storm spell).
            :50m:Active (5 STA):None</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="novice_preacherInvo_list_data">

        <item>Blessing of Fortune:1:The Blessing of Fortune
            gives the target LUCK points equal
            to half the value you rolled over
            DC of 12 (max 5).
            :10m:Until Expired:None</item>

        <item>Blessing of Love:2:The Blessing of Love gives
            the caster a +3 to Charisma and
            Seduction for the duration of the
            invocation.
            :5m:1d10 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Holy Light:1:Holy Light lights up an area
            as though the caster was carrying
            a torch. The light gives off no heat
            and cannot be used to ignite other
            objects like a torch can.
            :Self:3d10 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Vaults of Knowledge:3:Vaults of Knowledge
            allows you to reach back into your
            mind and access any knowledge or
            memory that you’ve ever known as
            if you were just experiencing it.
            :Self:Immediate:None</item>

        <item>Waters of Clearance:1:Waters of Clearance sobers
            the target immediately. This incantation counteracts alcohol and
            alchemical solutions that cause intoxication.
            :5m:Immediate:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Web of Lies:3:Web of Lies allows you to
            scramble the information in a target’s head, making them question
            every piece of information and
            memory. This stuns the target.
            Once per round, on their turn, the
            target can roll 1d10. If they roll under their INT the effect ends.
            :8m:INT roll ends:Resist Magic</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="journeyman_preacherInvo_list_data">

        <item>Cleansing Fire:6:Cleansing Fire ignites one
            target, doing 3d6 damage and setting them on fire.
            :10m:Until Put Out:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Holy Fortification:5:Holy Fortification bolsters
            a target’s willpower and allows the
            target to make a new check against
            the effects of any spell that is currently affecting them.
            :10m:Immediate:None</item>

        <item>Light of Truth:4:The Light of Truth allows
            you to create a bright white light
            that forces one target to speak
            truthfully. Every round the target
            must make another check. If they
            fail, they must answer any question truthfully.
            :5m:Active (2 STA):Resist Magic</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="master_preacherInvo_list_data">

        <item>Divine Portal:12:Divine Portal creates a standing portal for a
            brief instant. The portal lasts for just one round and
            allows you to transport yourself or others anywhere
            you can recall. This portal otherwise functions like the
            mage spell, Standing Portal.
            :N/A:1 Round:None</item>

        <item>Divine Wisdom:10:Divine Wisdom searches
            with a powerful augury for the answer to a question.
            This answer cannot predict the future.
            The GM sets your DC based on the secrecy of the information.
            :50m:Active (5 STA):None</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="archPriestInvo_list_data">

        <item>Blessing of Death:16:Summoning the power of the Lion-Headed
            Spider, you cut the ties of life holding a target to this
            world. The target must roll Resist Magic or be thrust
            into Death state as if by taking normal damage. However
            if they are treated with a successful First Aid or
            Healing Hands roll at a DC of 16, they immediately
            recover their previous number of Health Points.
            :10m:Immediate:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Eternal Judgement:16:Using the power granted to you by the Eternal
            Fire, you cause a target to burst into a bright white
            fire, tinged with red. The fire does double the normal
            fire damage and cannot be extinguished except
            by magic, or by completely submerging underwater
            for 3 rounds. Anything that touches this magical fire
            ignites with normal fire and can be put out in one full round.
            :10m:Until Put Out:Resist Magic</item>

        <item>Freya\' Bravery:16:Calling upon the power of the goddess Freya,
            you summon her spirit into your body, creating a
            glow around yourself which emanates 20m in all directions. Every
            person within that area is emboldened
            by Modron Freya\'s love and guidance. They become
            immune to fear and gain 25 Health Points for the duration of
            the spell. If they leave the area of the invocation, its effects
            last for 1d6 rounds. These rounds renew if the person
            re-enters the area of the invocation
            and leaves again. This invocation affects those who
            don\'t believe in Freya, but the power can be withheld
            from anyone the caster chooses.
            :20m Radius:20 Rounds:None</item>

        <item>Healing Rest:16:With the power granted to you by Melitele, the
            mother goddess, you can place a number of people
            equal to the value of your Spell Casting skill into a
            deep coma in which their bodies heal themselves.
            They cannot act for the entirety of the rest and are
            unaware of their surroundings even if touched, moved,
            or attacked. At the end of the rest, targets revive at full
            health. If they had any critical wounds that had been
            treated, these wounds have been healed. This does not
            remove permanent penalties from Deadly Critical
            Wounds.
            :5m:1 Day:None</item>

        <item>Luck of the Father:16:With power granted to you by Kreve, the
            All-Father, you gather divine providence to you. For
            the duration of the spell you can spend a number of
            LUCK points equal to your Spell Casting skill value
            times 3. You can augment any rolls you make, but can
            also impose penalties or grant bonuses to the roll of
            anyone within 10m.
            :Self/10m:1 Hour:None</item>

        <item>White Flame:16: Summoning the power of the Great Sun, you
            create a bright aura of White Fire which lights the surrounding
            area to the level of bright light. This aura of
            fire doesn\'t burn anyone who touches it but does thaw
            anyone in the spell’s area, and dispels water-based
            spells in the area. Water-based spells can only be cast
            in the area of the spell if the caster’s Spell Casting
            check beats that of the Priest of the Great Sun. On top
            of this, any monster in the area that is vulnerable to
            sunlight takes double the normal penalties.
            :10m Radius:1 Hour:Resist Magic</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>