<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="minor_gifts_list_data">

        <item>Calm Animals:1:As an action, you can calm a Beast that
            does not have a Medium or Hard Threat Rating. After this
            effect, the Beast considers you and your allies friendly
            and will not attack unless provoked.:
            Beasts of Threat Rating Medium or Hard are enraged
            by your presence and if possible, will prioritize
            attacking you over other targets.
            :N/A</item>

        <item>Fear Aura:1:As an action, you are able to emit an aura of
            palpable fear. Everyone within 4m of you must make a DC-12
            Resist Magic check or be frightened and take a -2 to any
            action made against you for 24 hours.:
            You count as one level lower on the Social Standing Chart
            (Minimum Hated) and members of your own race now treat you
            as Tolerated instead of Equal.
            :N/A</item>

        <item>Fleet of Foot:1:As an action, you can double the
            range of your LEAP for 1 Round.:
            When you are knocked back, you travel an additional 4m,
            raising the possible damage taken from hitting an object.
            :N/A</item>

        <item>Green Thumb:1:As an action, you can grow a small plant
            from seed to maturity. This allows you to grow herbs and
            alchemical plants but not larger plants such as trees.:
            Any alchemical concoction you create with a plant-derived
            substance as one of its ingredients gives you the poisoned
            condition as well as the intended effect when you use it.
            :N/A</item>

        <item>Minuscule Illusion:1:As an action, you are able to create an
            illusion within 4m that fills a 1m cubed space. This illusion
            must be simple and is only visual.:
            You take a -3 penalty to determining whether an illusion is real or not.
            :N/A</item>

        <item>Pigment:1:As an action, you can make a mark with your hand
            on a surface that has a color you desire that can optionally
            glow, should you desire. The glowing mark raises the light
            level by 1 for 4m all around it (Maximum Daylight). Once
            you have made a mark you can take an another action as
            long as you are within 4m to make the mark emit a flash
            of Glaring Light for one round after which it disappears.:
            When someone within 10m of you suffers a magic fumble effect,
            you suffer the effect as well. If you suffer a magical
            fumble you do not suffer a second effect.
            :N/A</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="major_gifts_list_data">

        <item>Aerokinesis:2:As a full round action, you can manipulate
            up to 5 ENC of material at a range of 8m as if you were holding it.:
            Whenever you are knocked prone or knocked back you are also
            reduced to 10 STA unless you were currently at or below 10 STA.
            :9</item>

        <item>Cryokinesis:2:As a full round action, you can freeze
            up to 2 square meters of liquid or a single target within 8m.:
            Whenever you have a chance of being frozen, you are no matter what.
            Additionally, instead of the standard Frozen condition you reduce your SPD by 6 and REF by 4.
            :9</item>

        <item>Detect Poison:2:As a full round action, you can smell a substance
            to detect whether it has been poisoned.:
            Whenever you would gain the Intoxicated or Poisoned conditions,
            you are additionally Nauseated for the duration of those conditions.
            :9</item>

        <item>Fortify:2:As a full round action, you can increase the Reliability
            or SP of an item you can touch by 1. An item can only benefit from Fortify once.:
            If you come within 4m of any amount of dimeritium you lose all
            Vigor Threshold and must make an Endurance roll at a -3 against
            the Dimeritium Effect Table.
            :9</item>

        <item>Geokinesis:2:As a full round action, you can create a tremor
            with a 8m radius centered on yourself. Anyone within this
            area must make a DC-14 Athletics check or fall prone and be staggered.:
            If you would suffer the Staggered condition you are instead Stunned for 1 round.
            :9</item>

        <item>Pyrokinesis:2:As a full round action, you can light a fire
            or put out a fire. You can light one object or target within
            8m on fire. You cannot target yourself with this ability.:
            Whenever you have a chance of being caught on fire you are caught on fire no matter what.
            :9</item>

        <item>See Aura:2:As a full round action, you can see the aura
            of all targets within 8m of you. This aura tells you
            what the Vigor Threshold of each target is.:
            You give off a tangible tingle that alerts anyone who
            touches you to your magical capability. This will make
            many people assume you are a mage. Because of this your
            Social Standing is considered to be that of a mage.
            :9</item>

        <item>Weapon Honing:2:As a full round action, you can add
            a 25% Bleed chance to a weapon that deals Piercing or Slashing damage.:
            Whenever you have a chance of bleeding, you bleed
            no matter what.
            :9</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>