<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="profession_help">
         1. Defining Skill\n
        Each profession has a defining skill. This
        one skill separates this profession from all
        of the others—an ability that only a person
        with years of training in that field can acquire.
        The defining skill is counted in the
        profession skill package when buying skills.\n\n

        2. Vigor\n
        Each profession has a starting allowance of
        Vigor, which represents how much primal
        chaos you can channel through your body
        safely to cast spells, perform rituals, and
        inflict hexes.\n\n

        3. Magic Perks\n
        Professions with inherent magic have magic
        perks. These are spells, incantations, hexes,
        rituals, and signs.\n\n

        4. Skill Package\n
        Each profession has a skill package which
        represents general learning over the course
        of an apprenticeship.\n\n

        5. Starting Gear\n
        Each profession has starting gear that you
        can choose from. This are items that you
        would probably have and use in your daily
        life, working in that profession.\n\n

    </string>

    <string-array name="professions_defSkills_array">
        <item>Bard:Busking</item>
        <item>Criminal:Practiced Paranoia</item>
        <item>Craftsman:Patch Job</item>
        <item>Doctor:Healing Hands</item>
        <item>Mage:Magic Training</item>
        <item>Man At Arms:Tough As Nails</item>
        <item>Priest:Initiate of the Gods</item>
        <item>Witcher:Witcher Training</item>
        <item>Merchant:Well Traveled</item>
        <item>Noble:N/A</item>
        <item>Peasant:N/A</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="defSkills_data_array">

        <item>Busking:A Bard is a wonderful thing to have around,
            especially when the party’s low on money. A
            Bard can take an hour and make a Busking
            roll in the nearest town center. The total of
            this roll is the amount of money raked in by
            the Bard while they perform on the street. A
            fumble can lower the roll, and a negative value
            means that not only do you fail to make any
            coin but you are also harassed by the locals
            for your poor performance, resulting in a -2
            to Charisma with anyone in the town for the
            rest of the day</item>

        <item>Practiced Paranoia:Whether they’re an assassin, a thief,
            a counterfeiter, or a smuggler, criminals all share a practiced
            paranoia that keeps them out of trouble.
            Whenever a Criminal comes within 10m of a
            trap (this includes experimental traps, Man at
            Arms booby traps, and ambushes) they immediately can make a Practiced Paranoia roll at
            either the DC to spot the trap, the ambushing
            party’s Stealth roll, or a DC set by the GM.
            Even if they don’t succeed in spotting the trap,
            they are still aware that something is wrong</item>

        <item>Patch Job:A skilled craftsman can patch a weapon or
            armor well enough to keep it working and
            keep its wearer/wielder in the fight, whether
            that be by tying a bowstring back together, sharpening the edge of a broken blade or
            nailing a plate over a cracked shield. By taking
            a turn to roll Patch Job at a DC equal to the
            item’s Crafting DC -3 a Craftsman can restore
            a broken shield or armor to 1/2 its full SP or
            restore a broken weapon to 1/2 its durability.
            Until fixed at a forge, a patched weapon does
            half its normal damage.</item>

        <item>Healing Hands:Anyone can apply some ointment and wrap
            a bandage around a cut, but a Doctor has
            true medical training which allows them to
            perform complex surgeries. A Doctor with
            Healing Hands is the only person who can
            heal a critical wound. To heal critical wounds
            a doctor must make a number of successful
            Healing Hands rolls based on the severity of
            the critical wound. The DC of the roll is based
            on the severity of the critical wound as well.
            Healing Hands can also be used for any First
            Aid task.</item>

        <item>Magic Training:To qualify as a Mage a magically
            adept person must pass through the halls of one of the
            world’s magical academies and learn the
            fundamentals of the magical arts. A Mage can roll
            Magical Training whenever they encounter
            a magical phenomenon, an unknown spell,
            or a question of magical theory. The DC is set
            by the GM, and a success allows the Mage to
            learn everything there is to know about the
            phenomenon. Magical Training can also
            be rolled as a form of Awareness that detects
            magic that is in use, or specters.</item>

        <item>Tough As Nails:True Men At Arms like the Blue
            Stripes of Temeria and the Impera Brigade of Nilfgaard are
            hardened soldiers who never give in or surrender.
            When a Man At Arms falls to or below 0 Health, they can roll Tough As Nails at
            a DC equal to the number of negative Health
            times 2 to keep fighting. If they fail, they fall
            into death state as per usual. If they succeed
            they can keep fighting as if they were only at
            their Wound Threshold. Any damage forces
            them to make another roll against a DC based
            on their Health.</item>

        <item>Initiate of the Gods:The churches of the world are often warm
            and inviting places, helping their communities and welcoming new converts. A Priest
            can roll Initiate of the Gods at a DC set by
            the GM at churches of the same faith to get
            free lodging, healing, and other services at
            the GM’s discretion. Initiate of the Gods also
            works when dealing with members of the
            same faith, though they will likely be able to
            offer less than a fully supplied church. Keep in
            mind that Initiate of the Gods does not work
            with members of other faiths.</item>

        <item>Witcher Training:Most of a Witcher’s early life is spent within
            the walls of their keep, studying huge, dusty
            tomes and going through hellish combat
            training. Many have argued that the Witcher’s
            greatest weapon is their knowledge of monsters
            and their adaptability in any situation.
            When in a hostile environment or difficult
            terrain, a Witcher can lessen the penalties by
            half their Witcher Training value (minimum
            1). Witcher Training can also be used in any
            situation that you would normally use Monster Lore for</item>

        <item>Well Traveled:Your average merchant makes a living from
            trade and that trade brings in customers
            from all around. But a traveling merchant
            goes to their customers, wandering the roads
            of the world, and learning from it’s people.
            A Merchant can make a Well Traveled roll
            anytime they want to know a fact about a
            specific item, culture, or area. The DC is set
            by the GM and if the roll is successful the
            Merchant remembers the answer to that
            question, calling on memories of the last time
            they travelled through the applicable area.</item>

        <item>N/A:No defining skill information.</item>
        <item>N/A:No defining skill information.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="profession_indices_array">

        <item>Bard:36,29,28,33,35,9,30,37,8,4,5,6</item>
        <item>Criminal:0,22,29,42,47,43,24,18,25,9</item>
        <item>Craftsman:22,38,1,39,3,27,30,35,26,9</item>
        <item>Doctor:38,1,28,45,2,33,50,18,8,12</item>
        <item>Mage:3,32,46,33,49,51,37,8,48,19</item>
        <item>Man At Arms:45,14,47,26,12,10,13,15,18,19,20,21,22,23</item>
        <item>Merchant:1,28,3,31,33,4,5,6,35,50,18,9</item>
        <item>Merchant:1,28,3,31,33,4,5,6,35,50,18,9</item>
        <item>Priest:28,45,41,46,33,34,51,48,11,12</item>
        <item>Witcher:38,22,0,2,14,16,48,25,20,12</item>
        <item>Noble:1</item>

    </string-array>
</resources>