<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="races_data_array">
        <item>Human: \nIn a world where non-humans can’t be trusted,
            humans look more trustworthy. Humans have
            an inherent +1 to their Charisma, Seduction,
            and Persuasion checks against other humans. (Trustworthy)\n

            Humans are clever and often have brilliant solutions to difficult problems.
            Humans gain an inherent +1 to Deduction. (Ingenuity)\n\n

            Part of the human race’s greatest strength is its
            willingness to charge forward endlessly, even
            into truly life-threatening situations. A human
            can summon up their courage and re-roll a failed
            Resist Coercion or Courage roll 3 times per
            game session. They take the higher of the two
            rolls, but if they still fail they cannot re-use the
            ability to roll again. (Blindly Stubborn)\n\n</item>

        <item>Dwarf: \nSpending much of their time in the mountains
            and mines, dwarves have naturally tough skin.
            As such a dwarfs’ skin has a natural stopping
            power of 2. This SP is applied on top of any armor the Dwarf is already wearing and cannot be
            lowered via weapon attacks or ablation damage. (Tough)\n\n

            Due to their compact frame and propensity
            for tough, physically demanding professions,
            dwarves gain a +1 to their Physique skill and
            raise their Encumbrance by 25. (Strong)\n\n

            With their eye for fine detail and appraisal it is
            hard to bluff a dwarf. Dwarves have an
            inherent +1 to their Business skill. (Crafter’s Eye)\n\n</item>

        <item>Elf: \nElves have a natural eye for beauty and a talent
            for artistic endeavours. Elves gain an inherent +1
            to their Fine Arts skill. (Artistic)\n\n

            Years of tradition and practice make elves some
            of the best archers in the world. Elves gain an
            inherent +2 to their Archery skill and can draw
            and string a bow without taking an action. (Marksman)\n\n

            Elves have a deep magical bond with nature itself. Elves do not disturb animals, meaning that
            any beast they encounter is considered friendly
            and will not attack unless provoked. Elves also
            automatically find any plant substance rated as
            commonly available (or lower) that they are
            seeking, as long as the substance would occur
            naturally in the surrounding terrain. (Natural Attunement)\n\n</item>

        <item>Witcher: \nDue to their heightened senses, witchers take no
            penalties from areas of dim light and gain an inherent +1 to their Awareness skill, as well as the
            ability to track things by scent alone. (Enhanced Senses)\n\n

            After all of the mutations required to become
            a witcher, they are immune to diseases and are
            able to use mutagens. (Resilient Mutation)\n\n

            Thanks to trauma and mutation, a witcher’s
            emotions are dulled. Witchers do not have to
            make courage checks against Intimidation, but
            they have a -4 to their Empathy Stat. This cannot
            bring Empathy below 1. (Dulled Emotions)\n\n

            After intensive training and mutation, witchers
            are much faster and more agile than humans.
            They gain a permanent +1 to their Reflex and
            Dexterity that can raise both stats above 10. (Lightning Reflexes)</item>

        <item>Halfling:N/A</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>