<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="novice_spells_list_data">

        <item>Afan\'s Mirror:3:Created by the talented
            Aedirnian mage Afan of Gulet, Afan\'s
            mirror creates 1d10 illusory copies
            of the caster. These copies are
            intangible, but indistinguishable
            from the caster and controlled by
            the caster’s mind. Controlling the
            copies does not require an action
            but they cannot leave the spell\’s
            range.
            :10m:Active (2 STA):None:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Alchemical Recovery:3:Alchemical Recovery
            allows you to revitalize the potency of a
            spent substance. Upon casting this spell,
            you can choose an alchemical crafting project
            that has failed and recover one of its Alchemical
            Substances. This spell cannot be cast on the
            same failed project more than once but can be
            used alongside the standard Recovery step.
            :2m:Immediate:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Blemish:5:Blemish allows you to create
            a small but noticeable illusion on a target
            that they are unaware of which makes them
            off-putting or unattractive. Upon casting
            this spell, the target suffers a -3 to Seduction,
            Charisma, and Leadership checks. If the target
            is alerted to the illusory blemish, they become
            aware of it. A target that looks in a mirror or
            reflective surface, can make a DC-16 Awareness
            check to notice it as well.
            :4m:1d6 Hours:Resist Magic:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Blinding Dust:3:Blinding Dust allows you to
            shoot a magical dust into the eyes
            of a target that blinds them for the
            duration of the spell.
            :4m:1d10:Dodge or Block:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Detect Ley Line:2:Detect Ley Line allows you
            to locate the closest Ley Line by sending out
            a magical pulse. Upon casting this spell, your
            hand points in the direction of the closest Ley
            Line and you can feel which element it is connected to.
            :1 Mile:Immediate:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Dispel:Variable:Dispel allows you to end a
            spell/ritual/hex within the range
            of this spell. This spell can cancel
            magic with a duration and can be
            used as a defensive action to block
            magic attacks with or without
            physical components. To cancel
            a magical effect you must spend
            half as many Stamina points as the
            caster spent to cast the magic and
            make a Spell Casting roll that beats
            their casting roll.
            :10m:Immediate:Spell Casting:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Fergus\' Demise:4:No one knows who created
            this spell but it was made infamous by its
            use on Emperor Fergus var Emreis. after he
            was dethroned. Fergus\' Demise allows you to
            summon a cluster of magical needles that act
            on your command, to torture a target within
            range. For the duration of this spell, you
            are able to make a Spell Casting check instead
            of an Intimidation check to interrogate your target.
            :2m:1 Hour:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Glamour:5:Glamour allows you to cast
            an illusion around yourself that
            makes you look stunning. This
            spell grants you +3 to Seduction,
            Charisma, and Leadership.
            :Self:1d6 Hours:None:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Hold Tongue:5:Hold Tongue allows
            you to magically glue a target\'s lips and paralyze their
            tongue, rendering the them unable to speak.
            While affected by this spell, the target cannot
            open their mouth and can only emit muffled sounds.
            If a Mage, Priest, or Druid with a Spell Casting
            skill value below 7 is affected by this spell,
            they cannot cast magic. At the end of every round,
            the target can attempt another Resist Magic
            check against a new Spell Casting check to end the effect.
            :10m:10 Minutes:Resist Magic:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Magic Compass:3:Magic Compass allows
            you to instantly determine the direction to a place you have been
            before. Alternately, the spell tells
            which direction is north.
            :Self:1d6 Hours:None:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Magic Screen:3:Magic Screen allows you to
            create a very specific illusion over a 2m cubed
            area to hide or alter items. Upon casting this
            spell, you can hide or change the appearance
            of items within the area. This change can only
            be visual and remains until dispelled or until
            any items are removed from that 2m cubed area. When
            a target comes within 4m of the Magic Screen they
            can make a Resist Magic check to see through the Illusion.
            :4m:Immediate:Resist Magic:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Reopen Portal:6:Reopen Portal allows you to find
            the trace of an existing portal and reopen that
            connection temporarily. Upon casting this spell,
            you can choose either a Permanent Portal which is
            currently closed or the trace of a Standing Portal
            which was cast within the last 30 seconds and roll
            a Spell Casting check. If the chosen portal is a
            Permanent Portal, the DC to reopen it is 16. If
            the chosen portal is a Standing Portal, the DC is 20.
            :2m:1 Round:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Savolla\'s Method:5:An evolution of ancient techniques,
            Savolla\'s Method breaks down the tissue and mucous
            membranes of a corpse and makes it easier to find and
            extract mutagenic compounds. Upon casting this spell,
            the Mutagen within a corpse separates itself and emits
            a slight glow allowing it to be extracted with a DC-14
            Alchemy or Witcher Training Check.
            :2m:Immediate:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Summon Staff:2:Summon Staff allows you
            dematerialize your staff and transport
            it to a place you have been
            within the last day. You can cast
            the spell again to summon the staff
            back to you.
            :N/A:Immediate:None:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Telepathy:2:Telepathy allows you to
            communicate telepathically with
            one subject for the duration of the
            spell. Telepathy crosses language
            barriers.
            :10m:Active (1 STA):None:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Cenlly Graig:3:Cenlly Graig hurls sharp
            stones at your opponent. For every
            point you roll above your opponent’s
            defense (maximum 10) you
            deal 1d6 damage. Each roll counts
            as its own attack.
            :5m:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Earth</item>

        <item>Codi Bywyd:2:Codi Bywyd can grow a
            small plant from seed to maturity in one turn.
            This allows you to
            grow herbs and alchemical plants,
            but not larger plants such as trees.
            :4m:Immediate:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Cryfhau:4:Cryfhau allows you to permanently
            increase the density of a single 2m cubed area
            of cover. Upon casting this spell, you immediately
            raise the cover\'s SP by 5. This can raise the SP
            higher than its original total. Cryfhau cannot
            be cast multiple times on the same area.
            :2m:Immediate:None:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Diagnostic Spell:3:Diagnostic Spell allows you
            to quickly assess a person’s health
            and determine how many Health
            Points they have, what critical
            wounds they have, and if they are
            sick or poisoned.
            :5m:Immediate:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Earthen Pillar:4:Earthen Pillar allows you
            raise a 2m cubed pillar from earthen ground.
            This pillar counts as cover with 10 SP and
            remains until destroyed.
            :10m:Immediate:None:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Earthen Spike:5:Earthen Spike creates an
            angled stalagmite to stab up into
            the target. This spike does 5d6
            damage and remains until destroyed.
            It can be destroyed by doing 20
            points of damage to it.
            :6m:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Earth</item>

        <item>Korath\'s Breath:2:Korath\'s Breath breaks
            down a nearby stone or earth surface and sprays burning sand in
            a 3m cone in front of you. Opponents in that area that fail
            their defense are blinded for 1d6 rounds.
            :3m Cone:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Earth</item>

        <item>Luthien\'s Quill:2:Named for its inventor,
            Luthien of Ebbing, Luthien\'s Quill
            can etch writing or drawings into
            any solid surface. It cannot be used
            on living creatures.
            :1m:Immediate:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Magic Healing:5:Magic Healing stimulates
            the natural healing of a target to
            heal them at a rate of 3 points of
            damage per round. This lasts for
            the duration of the spell. Alternatively,
            this spell can be used repeatedly to heal a critical wound.
            :2m:1d10 Rounds:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Sharpen Senses:2:Sharpen Senses allows you
            to heighten the sensitivity of your sight,
            smell, and hearing. Upon casting this spell,
            you immediately gain the benefits of Night
            Vision and Scent Tracking and have a +2 to
            Awareness checks. However, if you are subjected
            to a bright light or a very loud noise,
            you suffer Staggered condition.
            :Self:30 Minutes:None:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Soften Earth:2:Soften Earth allows you to
            soften a 6m cubed area of earth into a muddy
            morass or change sand into quicksand. The area
            of the spell becomes difficult to maneuver
            within and imposes a -2 to Dodge/Escape and Athletics checks.
            :10m:2d10 Rounds:None:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Talfryn\'s Prison:3:Talfryn\'s Prison is named
            for Talfryn of Nazair, a treacherous knight who was trapped for
            three days in the garden of the
            magician Drystan. The spell allows
            you to bind a target in roots. The
            roots take 15 points of damage to
            break. Otherwise a Dodge/Escape
            check must be made at a DC equal
            to your original Spell Casting roll
            to escape.
            :10m:Until Destroyed:Dodge:Earth</item>

        <item>Adenydd:4:Adenydd allows you to
            lighten yourself slightly and create
            a simple glide path when falling.
            This means for each 2m you fall
            you travel 2m in a direction. If you
            make it to the ground within the
            duration of the spell you take no
            damage.
            :Self:Active (2 STA):None:Air</item>

        <item>Air Pocket:3:Air Pocket allows you to
            create a pocket of fresh air underwater
            or in an area where there
            normally wouldn\'t be fresh air. The
            pocket has a 1m radius for the duration of the spell.
            :12m:2d10 Rounds:None:Air</item>

        <item>Bronwyn\'s Bow:2:Developed by Bronwyn Deadeye
            to bombard the Nilfgaardian Navy, this spell allows
            you to summon a powerful current of air to propel
            a thrown weapon great distances. Upon casting this
            spell, you can make an attack with any Thrown Weapon,
            handheld Ranged Weapon Ammunition (Arrows or Bolts),
            or Bomb against a target using your Spell Casting base.
            If throwing an arrow or bolt, you deal 4d6 damage.
            :50m:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Bronwyn\'s Gust:2:Bronwyn\'s Gust is named
            after the Skellige mage and raider,
            Bronwyn Deadeye. The spell
            allows you to knock a target back
            a number of meters equal to the
            number of points you rolled over
            the opponent’s defense. This attack
            only does 1d6 damage, but if your
            opponent strikes something they
            take ramming damage.
            :2m:Immediate:Dodge:Air</item>

        <item>Dust Coating:3:Dust Coating allows you to whip
            up dust from the local area into a 10m cubed
            cloud which reveals any invisible creatures for
            one round. Choose one target within this area to
            adhere the dust to. If the target fails to defend,
            you cover them in a coating of dust which negates
            the benefits of invisibility.
            :20m:Active (2 STA):Dodge:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Freshen Air:2:Freshen Air allows you to
            clear a 4m radius area (centered
            around you) of any smoke, poison,
            or any other tainted air for the duration of the spell.
            :2m Radius:Active (2 STA):None:Air</item>

        <item>Light Feet:2:Light Feet allows you to accelerate
            your movement by carrying yourself along on a
            gust of wind. Upon casting this spell, you raise
            your Speed Statistic by 5, your Run Derived Statistic
            by 15, and your Leap Derived Statistic by 3.
            :Self:Active (2 STA):None:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Magnify Odor:5:Magnify Odor allows you to intensify
            an existing scent until it encompasses a 6m cubed area.
            A creature who starts their turn in this area or enters
            it must make an Endurance check against your Spell
            Casting check or be overwhelmed by the odor and Nauseated
            for 1 Minute. Additionally, anyone who enters the area is
            permeated by the scent for 1 week along with their
            possessions granting anyone with Scent Tracking a +2 to
            track them. Any creature with Scent Tracking loses that
            ability while affected by this spell. This scent lasts
            for the duration of the spell or until entirely submerged in water.
            :10m:1 Week:None:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Urien\'s Shelter:3:Urien\'s Shelter, created by
            the nautical air magician Urien of
            Cidaris, allows you to negate hostile
            weather effects in an 8m radius
            centered on you. This negates extreme
            heat, extreme cold, rain, and snow.
            :8m Radius:1d6 Hours:None:Air</item>

        <item>Static Storm:5:Static Storm allows you to
            infuse a 5m radius centred around
            you with electricity. Anyone within
            this area (excluding you) who is
            wearing metal armor or carrying
            metal weapons takes 2 points of
            damage per round.
            :5m Radius:2d6 Rounds:None:Air</item>

        <item>Telekinesis:3:Telekinesis allows you to
            lift and manipulate an object (up
            to 5 ENC per 1 point of Spell Casting)
            as though you were holding it.
            :5m:Active (2 STA):None:Air</item>

        <item>Zephyr:5:Zephyr allows you to shoot
            out a burst of wind that blasts anyone
            within 2m of you back 6m.
            This attack does only 1d6 damage,
            but if your opponent hits something they
            suffer ramming damage.
            :2m Radius:Immediate:None:Air</item>

        <item>Aenye:5:Aenye allows you to throw
            a ball of pure fire at an opponent
            within the range of the spell. This
            ball of fire does 4d6 damage and
            has a 75% chance of lighting the
            target on fire.
            :12m:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Fire</item>

        <item>Aine Verseos:1:Aine Verseos creates an
            area of bright light in a 4m radius
            centred on you.
            :4m Radius:Active (2 STA):None:Fire</item>

        <item>Brand of Fire:4:Brand of Fire allows you
            to brand a target with a simple
            symbol or word anywhere on their
            exposed body. This does 1d6 damage
            to the target and leaves a large,
            permanent scar.
            :8m:Immediate:None:Fire</item>

        <item>Breath of Fire:4:An imperfect attempt by the
            sorcerer Afan of Gulet to re-create the breath
            of a true dragon, Breath of Fire allows you to
            exhale a stream of magical fire onto a target.
            If the target fails their defense, they take 3d6
            damage and have a 100% chance of being lit on fire.
            :4m:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Cadfan\'s Grasp:4:Cadfan\'s Grasp, named for
            the magician and smith Cadfan of
            Ebbing, allows you to super-heat
            a metal item, making the holder
            drop the item or take 2d6 damage
            to the limb holding it. Alternatively,
            the spell can heat weapons
            to give +2d6 damage and a 50%
            chance to ignite a target.
            :8m:1d6 Rounds:None:Fire</item>

        <item>Coating of Fire:3:Coating of Fire allows
            you to subtly permeate a single object with
            fire magic to make it highly flammable. For
            the duration of the spell, the object will burst
            into flame immediately if exposed to any open
            flame. If cast on a creature any effect that
            would have a chance to light them on fire
            automatically does.
            :2m:1 Hour:Dodge:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Harmless Fire:3:Harmless Fire allows you to manipulate
            the heat and power of a fire to make it temporarily safe.
            Upon casting this spell, choose an area of fire no larger
            than 2m cubed and that fire becomes harmless to anyone
            touching it. The fire will not spread or otherwise damage
            anything it is touching. If you are on fire and under the
            effect of this spell you can still take damage from fire-based attacks.
            :8m:10 Minutes:None:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Magic Flare:2:Magic Flare creates a bright
            flash above you. Everyone within
            an 8m radius must make a Resist
            Magic check or be blinded for 1d6
            rounds. This flare can be seen for
            10 kilometers.
            :8m Radius:Immediate:Resist Magic:Fire</item>

        <item>Raise Flame:3:Raise Flame allows you to
            spread an existing fire at a speed
            of 2m per round in any direction,
            dull down a fire to a weak blaze
            (lowering the fire damage by 1), or
            intensify the fire (raising the fire
            damage by 1).
            :10m:Active (2 STA):None:Fire</item>

        <item>Tanio Ilchar:3:Tanio Ilchar creates a burst
            of fire in a 2m by 2m area. This has
            a 100% chance of lighting a target
            in the area on fire.
            :8m:Immediate:Dodge:Fire</item>

        <item>Vahila\'s Smoke:3:Created by the feared Etolian
            assassin Vahila, this spell transforms a wisp of
            smoke into a choking veil. Upon casting this spell,
            you can engulf a single target\'s head in thick smoke.
            If this target fails to defend they are immersed in
            smoke and considered Blinded and Suffocating. Each turn,
            the target can spend their action to attempt another
            defense check against a new Spell Casting check to
            end the effect.
            :10m:Active (2 STA):Dodge:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Wave of Fire:4:Wave of Fire shoots a 3m
            cone of fire in one direction that
            does 2d6 damage to anyone who
            isn’t able to dodge or block, and
            has a 50% chance of igniting a
            target.
            :3m Cone:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Fire</item>

        <item>Aurora\'s Breath:5:Developed by the famed
            Water Mage, Aurora Henson, to explore submerged
            ruins off the coast of the Continent, Aurora\'s
            Breath allows you to breath water as well as air
            through skillful manipulation of water magic.
            :Self:30 Minutes:None:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Carys\' Hail:3:Named for its creator
            Carys of Cintra, this spell hurls
            pellets of ice at high speeds at 1
            opponent. For every 1 point you
            roll over your opponent’s Dodge/
            Block (maximum 5), you deal 1d6
            damage and have a 25% chance to
            freeze your opponent. Each roll
            counts as its own separate attack
            when determining location and
            dealing damage.
            :5m:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Water</item>

        <item>Control Water:5:Control Water allows you
            to control the speed at which a
            body of water is moving and in
            what direction it’s moving for the
            duration of the spell. This can be
            used to slow swimming targets
            by half, speed up ships by half, or
            slow or halt river currents.
            :10m:Active (2 STA):DC set by the GM:Water</item>

        <item>Curse of Sedna:5:Named after the tumultuous Sedna Abyss, which is considered a suicidal destination for
            ships, Curse of Sedna creates a
            powerful whirlpool in a 4 meter area.
            Anyone within 5m must
            make a Swimming check equal
            to your Spell Casting check or be
            dragged underwater. They must
            make a check each round or remain
            underwater, where they will
            start suffocating.
            :12m:Active (2 STA):Dodge:Water</item>

        <item>Dormyn\'s Fog:3:Created by Dormyn of
            Gemmera, Dormyn\'s Fog creates
            an area with a 10m radius, centred
            on you, of thick fog which puts anyone
            in it at a -3 to Awareness and
            limits vision range to 4m.
            :10m Radius:Active (2 STA):None:Water</item>

        <item>Downpour:2:Downpour creates a 10m
            radius area of rain that puts out
            any fire it hits. This spell
            counteracts fire effects.
            :8m:Active (2 STA):None:Water</item>

        <item>Ice Slick:2:Ice Slick allows you to
            create a 2m square area of ice. Anyone
            who crosses that area must make
            an Athletics check at a DC equal to
            your Spell Casting check or trip on
            the ice.
            :10m:2d10 Rounds:Dodge:Water</item>

        <item>Puro Dwr:2:Puro Dwr allows you to
            purify 1 cubic meter of water. This
            negates poison and disease, but
            will not force living creatures out
            of it. If cast on a small part of a
            larger body of polluted water, the
            water will begin to pollute again
            after the duration of the spell ends.
            :4m:1d10 Rounds:None:Water</item>

        <item>Rhewi:2:Rhewi creates a thick layer
            of ice around a target for the duration
            of the spell. The target is treated as
            frozen. If used on a non-living target,
            the target cannot to be manipulated or moved.
            :8m:1d10 Rounds:Dodge:Water</item>

        <item>Slip Stream:5:Slip Stream allows you to
            propel yourself through the water in a
            current of your own creation. While swimming,
            your Speed Statistic is changed to 12 and you
            do not suffer the normal penalties for
            attacking and defending underwater.
            :Self:10 Minutes:None:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Water Jet:5:Water Jet creates a controlled
            geyser from a source of water to strike a
            target with your choice of slashing, piercing,
            or bludgeoning damage. If the target fails to
            defend, they take 4d6 damage and are knocked Prone.
            :Self:10 Minutes:None:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Web of Ice:5:Web of Ice allows you to create a
            delicate structure of ice on a surface which is
            linked to a duplicate that you possess. The moment
            a creature interacts with the surface it is placed
            on, the structure and its duplicate break. Alternatively,
            breaking the duplicate melts the original structure.
            The ice can be spotted with a DC-18 Awareness check.
            :2m:1 Day:None:Water:toc</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="journeyman_spells_list_data">

        <item>Cloak:16:Cloak allow you to render yourself and anything
            you are carrying invisible. This grants you a +10 to Stealth
            and a +5 to Attack and Defense. Even if a creature makes
            their Awareness check to spot you, you still gain a +3
            to Attack and Defense. Yrden or a Moondust Bomb can
            render you partially visible, reducing your Stealth
            bonus to +5 and your Attack and Defense bonus to +3.
            If you are hit by an attack while invisible, this spell ends immediately.
            :Self:Active (2 STA):None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Disrupt Focus:15:Disrupt Focus allows you to temporarily
            disturb the magical pathways in an item with the Focus
            effect. Upon casting this spell, a single item with
            the Focus effect ceases to act as a focus for the duration of the spell.
            :10m:10 Minutes:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Dormyn\'s Chamber:18:Dormyn\'s Chamber allows
            you to imprison a single target within a translucent
            magical bubble. The chamber has 40 Hit Points and
            remains stationary where it was cast. The creature
            within the chamber cannot target or be targeted by
            anything outside. Additionally, sound does not
            pass through the chamber\'s walls.
            :10m:Active (8 STA):Dodge:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Eilhart\'s Technique:12:Named for its creator Philippa
            Eilhart, this gruesome spell allows you
            to dig into a target\’s mind and tear out
            information. If you succeed on your
            Spell Casting roll you gain one piece of
            information from the target. If the target
            fumbles their defense, their INT is
            reduced by 1 permanently.
            :3m:Immediate:Resist Magic:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Empower:12:Empower allows you to weave additional
            magic into your spell casting to create a dangerous convergence
            of chaos. The next spell you cast gains one of the following benefits
            of your choice- the percentage chance of any effects caused by the
            spell raise to 100%, the roll to cast the spell is made at a +2
            bonus, or an already damaging spell deals an additional 2d6
            damage. However, if you roll a 1 when making the Spell Casting
            check you automatically suffer from a Magical Fumble as though you had rolled a 10.
            :Self:1 Minute:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Illusion:8:Illusion allows you to create
            any visual illusion you want within
            20m of yourself. Anyone who fails the
            Resist Magic check sees the illusion
            and believes it. The illusion cannot be
            touched, smelled, or heard, however.
            :20m:Active (4 STA):Resist Magic:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Spectral Tether:8:Spectral Tether allows you to
            weave a tether of magic around a target which binds
            it to it\'s physical form. While affected by this
            spell, a target cannot become incorporeal or invisible
            and cannot teleport by any means. Additionally, as
            long as the spell is in effect, the target cannot move
            more than 10m away from you. Each turn, the target can
            spend their action to attempt another Resist Magic
            check against a new Spell Casting check to end the effect.
            :10m:Active (4 STA):Resist Magic:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Teleportation:10:Teleportation allows you to
            teleport to a known location instantaneously.
            You cannot take anyone with
            you and can only transport the items
            on your person or in your hands. Attempting
            to teleport with a person
            simply teleports you and leaves them
            behind. Teleporting require a DC 15
            Spell Casting roll. If you fail the roll,
            you wind up in a random location 1d6
            miles away.
            :N/A:Immediate:None:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Trap Portal:12:Trap Portal allows you to place a
            magical trap inside a portal which redirects the
            portal\'s end point. Upon casting the spell, you
            learn the portal\'s end point and can choose a
            location within 1 mile of that point to be the
            new end point. This trap makes a notable change
            to the portal which requires a DC-16 Magic Training
            check or a DC-20 Education check to spot. Anyone
            with at least 1 point in Magic Training automatically
            gets to roll a Magic Training check upon seeing the
            portal to try and spot the trap. Immediately after
            a creature passes through the portal, the trap is
            dispelled but evidence that the portal was trapped
            remains for 1 month.
            :4m:1 Month:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Bekker\'s Rockslide:13:Bekker\'s Rockslide allows
            you to rip a large stone from beneath the ground
            and drop it on a target. Upon casting this spell,
            the target must roll a Reposition roll against your
            Spell Casting check. If they fail, the target takes
            6d6 damage to the torso with a 100% chance of Knock-Down.
            As the rock makes impact, it explosively shatters
            covering a 6m radius. Anyone in that area must make a
            DC-16 Athletics check or be Knocked-Down and take
            4d6 damage to the torso.
            :10m:Immediate:Dodge (Reposition):Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Elgan\'s Bastion:14:Created by the famed magician
            Elgan of Verden, Elgan\'s Bastion uses trace amounts
            of metal in stone to magnetically lift a shield of
            rocks around you to defend yourself from physical
            attacks and damage. This shield of rocks counts as a
            Cover with 30 SP and entirely surrounds you. While
            surrounded, your SPEED Statistic cannot be higher
            than 2 and you cannot do anything on your turn but
            take a single Movement Action.
            :Self:Active (4 STA):None:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Elgan\'s Theory:10:Elgan\'s Theory was discovered
            by Elgan of Verden who travelled to
            the heart of Mahakam and worked for
            years studying earth magic. The spell
            allows you to magnetize a metal object
            within 8m. Anything metal within 2m
            is drawn and sticks to the magnet. It
            takes a DC 18 Physique check to pry an
            object off. All metal that sticks to
            someone\'s weapons or armor counts against
            their ENC.
            :8m:2d10 Rounds:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Javed\'s Swarm:10:Javed\'s Swarm allows you to
            control a great number of insects from the environment.
            Upon casting this spell, a swarm of controlled insects
            crawls out from nearby crevices and forms a horde
            with a SPD Statistic of 7 which can engulf a single
            target by making an attack at a Base 14. This attack
            deals 1d6 damage to the target\'s torso, ignores all
            worn armor, and has a 100% chance of poisoning.
            The Horde has 15 Hit Points and a Dodge base of 14.
            :6m:10 Minutes:None:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Rhwystr Graig:15:Rhwystr Graig allows you to
            create a 2m by 3m rock wall with 30
            points of SP anywhere within 10m with
            any facing. This wall remains until destroyed.
            :20m:Until Destroyed:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Stammelford\'s Earthquake:12:Stammelford\'s
            Earthquake allows you to disrupt the ground in a
            10m area and create a jagged, crumbling
            terrain which puts everyone in
            the area at a -2 to Reflex and a -3 to
            SPD. Small structures on the shattered
            ground have a 10% chance of
            collapsing. Each round, a creature in
            the spell’s area must make an Athletics
            roll or sink into the crumbling ground,
            which causes them to suffocate until
            they make a successful Athletics check
            to climb out. After the duration of the
            spell ends, the ground stops churning
            but it will remain shattered.
            :20m:1d10 Rounds:Dodge:Earth</item>

        <item>Alzur\'s Thunder:15:Alzur\'s Thunder allows you
            to shoot a powerful lightning bolt
            at a target which does 8d6 damage
            and has a 75% chance of setting
            the target on fire. Alzur\'s Thunder
            can travel in a straight line through
            targets. For every target it passes
            through the damage to the next
            target decreases by 1d6.
            :25m:Immediate:Dodge:Air</item>

        <item>Ball Lightning:14:Favored by mages who commonly
            fight agile targets, Ball Lightning summons
            an orb of magical lightning which flies through
            the air at your command. Upon casting this spell,
            you can direct the ball lightning at a single target
            who must make a defense check against your Spell
            Casting check. If they fail, the target takes 3d6
            damage to the torso and suffers the Concussion
            Critical Injury Effect for 10 Minutes. If the
            target successfully defends, the Ball Lightning
            remains in the area. On subsequent turns you can
            use your action to make a new attack against a
            target with a new Spell Casting check. Once the
            ball lightning hits a target it dissipates.
            :20m:5 Rounds:Dodge:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Gwynt Troelli:12:Gwynt Troelli creates a
            barrier of wind around you that
            blocks ranged attacks and projectiles.
            Any projectile attack must
            beat your Spell Casting roll. If they
            fail, the barrier knocks the projectile
            8m away in a random direction.
            :10m Radius:Active (4 STA):None:Air</item>

        <item>Invisible Ribbon:15:With a whisper, Invisible
            Ribbon allows you to focus a gust of wind into a
            sharp, invisible blade that whistles through the
            air. Upon casting this spell, a single target must
            make a Defense check against your Spell Casting
            check. If they fail, the target takes 3d6 damage.
            The ribbon is invisible and thus even after
            attacking, anyone in the area must make a DC-20
            Perception check to determine where the attack came from.
            :10m:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Suffocate:14: Suffocates a target for 1d10
            damage per turn. The suffocation
            ends if the caster is struck with a
            weapon or stops focusing on the
            spell. While suffocating, a target is
            treated as staggered.
            :10m:Active (4 STA):Resist Magic:Air</item>

        <item>Touch of Lightning:8:Touch of Lightning allows you to
            imbue a stationary metal object with a powerful charge
            of electricity. Upon casting this spell, the object becomes
            an electrical trap which will deal 1d6 damage to the
            first body location that touches it. This spell can be
            charged by spending extra rounds focusing on it during
            the casting. For each round that you continue to hold the
            object and pay its active cost the trap deals an extra 1D6
            of damage (maximum 8D6 total). If the object is moved before
            it is touched by a body location it loses all charges.
            Additionally, 24 hours after the spell is cast the object
            loses all charges. It requires a DC-20 Perception check
            to determine an object has been affected by this spell.
            :2m:Active (5 STA):None:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Cinder Door:12:Cinder Door allows you to funnel
            fire magic. into a flammable structure. to safely
            and silently consume it from within. Upon casting
            this spell, up to a 2m cubed section of the cover
            you touch takes 4d6 ablation damage. This spell
            can be maintained by spending extra rounds focusing
            on it during the casting. For each. round that you
            continue to maintain the spell and pay its active
            cost the cover takes 4d6 ablation damage. When
            this area of cover no longer has any SP, it crumbles away.
            :2m:Active (3 STA):None:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Demetia\'s Crest Surge:12:Demetia\'s Crest
            Surge allows you to create a shield of pure
            fire magic around you that blocks
            a number of water spells equal to 2
            times your Spell Casting skill value.
            Projectiles that enter the shield
            are destroyed, and living creatures
            cannot enter the area of the shield.
            :10m:Active (4 STA):None:Fire</item>

        <item>Flaming Vortex:15:Flaming Vortex creates a
            flaming tornado 2m wide. You can
            direct the tornado to move a number
            of meters equal to your Spell
            Casting skill value per turn. If it
            runs over or into a target, make
            a Spell Casting roll versus their
            Dodge/Escape roll. If they fail,
            they take 5d6 damage and have a
            50% chance of being set on fire.
            The vortex will not travel beyond
            the spell’s range.
            :10m Radius:Active (4 STA):Dodge:Fire</item>

        <item>Mage\'s Forge:12:Mage\'s Forge allows
            you to create a magical fire that can be used
            to purify metal. When ingots of metal are placed
            within this fire. their impurities are burned.
            away making them easier to recover after a failed
            crafting attempt. During the Recovery Step any
            purified ingots used are automatically recovered.
            Additionally, the fire created acts as a Tinker\'s
            Forge for the purposes of crafting, but cannot be
            used on Dimeritium.
            :2m:1 Day:None:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Seirff Haul:10:Seirff Haul creates a
            number of serpents from fire magic
            that swarm over a target. The target
            is grappled and on fire until
            they make a Dodge/Escape check
            vs. your Spell Casting roll. Every
            round that the target fails the
            Dodge/Escape check, the DC rises
            by 1 point as the serpents tighten.
            :10m:2d10:Dodge:Fire</item>

        <item>Smith\'s Touch:10:Smith\'s Touch focuses fire magic
            into metal allowing you to manipulate it with your
            bare hands. While this spell is active, you are able
            to bend, shape, and manipulate metal as if it were clay.
            Additionally, by taking an action to make a Brawling attack,
            you can deal 3d6 ablation damage to armor or reliability
            damage to a weapon. This spell cannot be used on Dimeritium.
            :2m:Active (10 STA):None:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Anialwch:8:Anialwch allows you to
            suck some of the liquid from a target\'s
            body, damaging and exhausting them. The
            spell does 4d6 damage which cannot be blocked by
            armor or shields. The extreme dehydration
            creates a fatigue which
            lowers the target\'s current STA by
            4d6 as well.
            :10m:Immediate:Resist Magic:Water</item>

        <item>Invaerne:14:Invaerne allows you to create a
            howling snowy gale in an area with a 30m radius.
            This area has Snow and Ice conditions. If cast in
            a cold environment, the duration of this spell is increased to one week.
            :50m:1 Hour:None:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Merigold\'s Hailstorm:15:Named for its creator Triss
            Merigold, ex-advisor of King
            Foltest of Temeria, Merigold\'s
            Hailstorm creates a hailstorm encompassing the area of the spell.
            Everyone within the storm must
            make a Dodge/Escape check at
            a DC equal to your Spell Casting check each round or take 2d6
            damage to a body part.
            :30m Radius:Active (4 STA):Dodge:Water</item>

        <item>Rusting:14:Rusting allows you to emit a spray
            of chemically reactive water which rapidly oxidizes
            metal objects. If using this spell on a target\'s
            armor, all their worn armor takes 2d6 ablation
            damage and wearing any of it imposes a -2 to their
            Reflex, Dexterity, and Speed Statistics. If using
            this spell on a target\'s weapon, the weapon takes
            2d6 reliability damage and imposes a -2 to attacks
            made with it. If this spell is blocked by a shield,
            the shield takes 2d6 Reliability damage. The rust
            created by this spell can be removed from 10 items
            by taking an hour to make a DC-14 Crafting check.
            :4m:Permanent:Dodge or Block:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Essence of Potion:12:Essence of Potion allows
            you to take a single dose of any Decoction, Potion,
            or Elixir that has not yet been affected by this
            spell and magically transfer some of its properties
            into a unit of Essence of Water, transforming
            it into a copy of that item.
            :2m:Permanent:None:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Waves of the Naglfar:10:Created by a mage who
            claimed to have witnessed the ride
            of the Wild Hunt, this spell creates
            a wave of ice magic that spreads
            out 3m from you in all directions.
            Anyone who doesn\'t dodge or
            block the spell is frozen and takes
            4d6 damage.
            :3m Radius:Immediate:Dodge or Block:Water</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="master_spells_list_data">

        <item>Bekker\'s Dark Mirror:25:Bekker\'s Dark Mirror allows
            you to trap a creature\'s reflection in a reflective
            surface near them, draining their strength. Upon
            casting this spell, you can choose two of the target\'s
            Statistics and reduce them each by 1d6. This reduction
            affects Derived Statistics. Once drained, this Statistic
            remains lowered for the duration of the spell or until
            the mirrored surface containing the reflection is
            completely destroyed. The affected target casts no
            reflection until the spell ends. A creature without
            a reflection cannot be affected by Bekker\'s Dark Mirror.
            :10m:1 Month:Resist Magic:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Mental Command:25:Mental Command allows
            you to plant an order in the mind
            of a target. This command must be
            executed to the letter by the target.
            If the command is something the
            target would never do, they get a
            +5 to their Resist Magic check.
            :10m:Until Task is Done:Resist Magic:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Standing Portal:22:Standing Portal creates a
            1m by 2m floating portal up to 10m
            from you. Stepping through this
            portal teleports you anywhere you
            can recall. The portal can transport
            anything that fits through it. If you
            end the portal while something is
            partially through, the portal slices
            the object (or creature) in two.
            The person is counted as being
            dismembered, as per the Critical
            Wound. You can create a portal to
            a location you don’t know as per
            Teleportation.
            :N/A:Active (6 STA):None:Mixed Element</item>

        <item>Steal Spell:20:Steal Spell allows you to take
            control of another mage\'s spell and re-designate
            its target. When another mage casts a Non-Master
            level spell you can immediately force the mage to
            make a contested Spell Casting check against you.
            If you succeed at this check, you change the target
            of the spell to anyone within range of the original
            caster or yourself if the spell had a range of self.
            If the spell requires an attack check, use your
            Spell Casting check from the contested check. If
            the spell you steal is active, you remain in
            control of the spell but must pay its active cost.
            :10m:Immediate:None:Mixed Element:toc</item>

        <item>Crystal Stasis:25:Crystal Stasis allows you to
            cause crystals to grow up around a target and
            encase them entirely, placing them into an unaging,
            coma-like state. These crystals grow rapidly but
            not instantaneous and the spell must be maintained
            as per an Active Spell over three rounds. On the
            target\'s next turn, their body becomes sluggish
            and stiff, imposing a 3 to attack and defense
            and a -3 to their SPD. On their second turn,
            their body begins to be consumed by crystal
            and they additionally cannot move from where
            they stand. On their third turn, the target is
            entirely entombed in a pillar of crystal rendering
            them unconscious. If the mage is forced to stop
            maintaining this spell before the third round,
            the spell ends and the effects are reversed.
            Otherwise, the only way to reverse the effects
            are the use of the Dispel spell.
            :6m:Active (6 STA):Resist Magic or Dodge:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Polymorphism:22:Polymorphism allows you
            to take the shape of a serpent, a
            cat, a bird, or a dog. While in this
            form, you have the physical statistics
            of that animal (See Bestiary,
            pg.310). Any items on your person
            transform with you. You must cast
            the spell again to change back to
            your human form.
            :Self:Until Re-Cast:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Shape Earth:25:Shape Earth allows you to create
            a single structure composed of materials present
            at the site such as wood, stone, or earth that fills
            a 20m cubed cube. This structure can be whatever
            you wish, provided that it is simple in nature for
            example, a tremendous wall, a statue, or a fortification
            with a few rooms and simple furnishings. The structure
            will build itself over the next 10 minutes and will
            vary in SP from a wooden wall with 5 SP to a stone wall
            with 30 SP. This is determined by the GM.
            :6m:Permanent:None:Earth:toc</item>

        <item>Transmutation:25:Transmutation allows you
            to change the properties of a mineral or
            metal. You can change one
            unit of metal into any other metal,
            or change an imperfect gem into
            a perfect gem suitable for magic.
            Dimeritium or other metals in
            contact with dimeritium cannot
            be created or changed by this spell.
            :2m:Permanent:None:Earth</item>

        <item>Dervish:22:Created by a mysterious
            Offeri magician, Dervish allows
            you to create a 2m tornado around
            yourself. This tornado immediately redirects ranged attacks as per
            Gwynt Troelli and acts a Zephyr
            spell against anyone within 2m of
            you. You cannot run while within this tornado, or make attacks
            out of it. But if you move within
            2m of a target they are effected by
            Zephyr.
            :2m Radius:Active (6 STA):Dodge:Air</item>

        <item>Gwyntog:24:Gwyntog allows you to create a localized
            windstorm with up to a 40m radius. While this spell
            is in effect, gale force winds whip around the area making
            flight impossible and movement extremely difficult.
            Immediately, any flying creature is knocked out of
            the air and suffers damage as per normal. Ranged
            attacks made will fail to hit their intended target
            and land wherever the GM decides. Finally, any creature
            in the area must make an Athletics check DC-20 or be
            unable to take a Movement or Run Action during their turn.
            :100m:Active (6 STA):None:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Hand of the Tempest:25:Summoning the full force of gales,
            you exert a tremendous force on a target which can manifest
            in one of 3 ways. With a powerful updraft you can send a target
            who fails a Reposition check or object of 1000kg or lighter
            flying 14m into the air. The target begins to fall at the end
            of their next turn. Upon hitting the ground, the target and
            anything it hits takes 7d6 bludgeoning damage to the torso and
            are knocked prone. Alternatively, with a powerful gust you
            can flood a 14m cone with powerful wind. Anyone in this area
            who fails a Reposition check or could not escape the area
            of the spell with their reposition is knocked back 14m and
            takes ramming damage if they hit anything as they fly.
            Finally, you can manipulate an object up to 1000kg as
            though you were holding it in your hand.
            :20m:Immediate:None:Air:toc</item>

        <item>Lightning Storm:25:Lightning Storm allows you
            to create a lightning storm. Lightning strikes randomly around the
            area. Anyone (except you) in the
            area has a 35% chance of being
            struck by lightning. If they miss
            this roll, they must make a Dodge/
            Escape check or take 8d6 damage
            to the torso and have a 75% chance
            to be ignited.
            :20m Radius:Active (6 STA):Dodge:Air</item>

        <item>Blaze of the Korath:24:Blaze of the Korath allows
            you to create a sweltering aura with up to a 40m
            radius which eats away at creatures\' STA. Upon
            casting this spell, each creature in the area
            lowers their current STA by 2d6. Additionally,
            while in the area, creatures are incapable
            of taking the Recovery Action. If a creature
            is in the area at the start of its turn or
            enters the area on its turn, they lower their
            current STA by 2d6. If a target is reduced
            to 0 points of STA by this spell, they fall
            unconscious until they recover at least
            20 points of STA and make a successful Stun save.
            :100m:Active (4 STA):None:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Living Fire:25:Living Fire allows you to summon
            a small amount of life into a fire. While not as
            sentient or powerful as a Fire Elemental, this
            living fire is capable of taking a turn, at your
            Initiative. The Living Fire has a Speed Statistic
            of 5, is considered Incorporeal, and can cast
            Aenye, Wave of Fire, and Flaming Vortex, with a
            Spell Casting Base of 16 and infinite STA.
            The Living Fire cannot take extra actions
            and is destroyed if the fire is put out.
            :10m:10 Minutes:None:Fire:toc</item>

        <item>Melgar\'s Fire:25:This spell is well
            known for sowing chaos on the fields of the Pontar
            Valley. Melgar’s Fire allows you to rain balls
            of fire from the sky over a huge
            area. Anyone (except you) in the area has a
            75% chance of being struck by
            a ball of fire. If they miss this roll,
            they must defend at a DC equal to your
            Spell Casting check or take 4d6 damage to
            a random location and have a
            75% chance of being ignited.
            :40m Radius:2d6 Rounds:Dodge or Block:Fire</item>

        <item>Mirror Effect:25:Mirror Effect creates a blinding
            beam of light which does 10d6 damage. This laser can
            be dodged and blocked (destroying whatever blocks it)
            but it cannot be displaced by wind and can only be parried by a reflective
            surface, which still takes damage. Tge reflected laser goes off in a random
            direction. This spell uses the rays of the sun and cannot be used where the
            sun’s rays can’t penetrate. By the light of the moon or on overcast days, it
            does half damage.
            :20m:2d6 Rounds:Dodge or Block:Fire</item>

        <item>Ainfra\'s Extraction:22:Created by the famed Ainfra
            of Mag Turga, Ainfra\'s Extraction allows you to
            desiccate a target and then utilize their water for
            your own means. Upon casting this spell, a target
            that fails to defend lowers their current STA by 8d6
            and the caster may immediately cast Rhewi,
            Ice Slick, or Water Jet at no STA cost.
            :8m:Immediate:Resist Magic:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Deluge of Ys:24:Deluge of Ys allows you to summon
            a 20m cubed cube of water which floods out in all
            directions. Anyone caught in the area takes 5d6
            damage to the torso and must make a DC-24 Physique
            check or be knocked prone as water batters them.
            If cast in an open area, the water will flood outwards
            within the same turn it was cast. If cast in an
            enclosed space, the water fills the space,
            breaking any non-reinforced barriers and
            leaves the area entirely submerged.
            :40m:Immediate:None:Water:toc</item>

        <item>Part Water:25:Part Water allows you to create an open area in a body of water, up
            to 10m by 100m by 10m. Fish, monsters, and other creatures in the water
            are swept back with the water. You can pass in and out of the wall as easily
            as stepping in or out of a body of water without disturbing the walls. If used
            while in the water the effect pushes the caster aside as well. The area can
            be summoned in any orientation, even vertical.
            :10m Radius:Active (6 STA):None:Water</item>

        <item>Tryferi Gaeaf:22:Tryferi Gaeaf allows you to shoot a number of 2m spikes of ice equal
            to half your Spell Casting skill value at any number of targets within range.
            These spikes do 5d6 points of damage and, if they do damage through
            armor, freeze the opponent and do 2 point of damage each round until they
            are broken off with a DC 20 Physique check or by doing 20 points of damage
            to them. Otherwise, these spikes last for the duration of the spell. Each
            attack resolves separately.
            :20m:1d10 Rounds:Dodge or Block:Water</item>



    </string-array>

</resources>